YAMANOUCHI	B-GPE
,	O
Japan	B-GPE
_	O
``	O
ROSS	B-PER
IS	O
THE	O
CHAMPION	O
.	O

GIVE	O
THE	O
GOLD	O
BACK	O
!	O
''	O

The	O
words	O
were	O
written	O
in	O
black	O
marker	O
on	O
a	O
linen	O
hotel	O
napkin	O
,	O
and	O
the	O
young	O
man	O
holding	O
that	O
napkin	O
up	O
i	O
the	O
drizzle	O
at	O
the	O
bottom	O
of	O
the	O
snowboarding	O
halfpipe	O
run	O
this	O
morning	O
was	O
the	O
Canadian	B-GPE
rider	O
Michael	B-PER
Michalchuck	I-PER
.	O

``	O
I	O
made	O
it	O
last	O
night	O
because	O
I	O
believe	O
in	O
Ross	B-PER
,	O
''	O
said	O
Michalchuck	B-PER
,	O
20	O
,	O
from	O
Calgary	B-GPE
.	O

Ross	B-PER
Rebagliati	I-PER
,	O
the	O
Canadian	B-GPE
snowboarder	O
who	O
has	O
been	O
stripped	O
of	O
his	O
gold	O
medal	O
in	O
the	O
giant	O
slalom	O
by	O
the	O
International	B-ORG
Olympic	I-ORG
Committee	I-ORG
after	O
testing	O
positive	O
for	O
marijuana	O
,	O
was	O
not	O
one	O
of	O
the	O
spectators	O
Thursday	O
at	O
the	O
Kanbayashi	O
Snowboard	O
Park	O
.	O

But	O
he	O
was	O
unquestionably	O
the	O
central	O
figure	O
as	O
the	O
men	O
's	O
and	O
women	O
's	O
halfpipe	O
riders	O
made	O
their	O
Olympic	O
debuts	O
.	O

``	O
Ross	B-PER
won	O
fair	O
and	O
square	O
;	O
he	O
is	O
the	O
gold	O
medalist	O
,	O
and	O
no	O
one	O
can	O
deny	O
him	O
that	O
,	O
''	O
Michalchuck	B-PER
said	O
.	O

``	O
I	O
do	O
n't	O
understand	O
why	O
this	O
is	O
happening	O
.	O

He	O
is	O
a	O
friend	O
of	O
mine	O
,	O
and	O
he	O
should	O
be	O
given	O
the	O
gold	O
back	O
.	O

I	O
saw	O
him	O
before	O
this	O
,	O
and	O
he	O
was	O
on	O
top	O
of	O
the	O
world	O
.	O

This	O
should	O
never	O
have	O
happened	O
to	O
him	O
.	O
''	O

Michalchuck	B-PER
decided	O
to	O
make	O
his	O
very	O
public	O
appeal	O
on	O
Wednesday	O
night	O
,	O
and	O
when	O
he	O
finished	O
his	O
opening	O
run	O
,	O
he	O
unstrapped	O
his	O
board	O
,	O
took	O
the	O
napkin	O
from	O
his	O
girlfriend	O
and	O
calmly	O
held	O
it	O
up	O
to	O
the	O
photographers	O
and	O
television	O
camera	O
operators	O
waiting	O
in	O
the	O
finish	O
area	O
.	O

``	O
I	O
think	O
the	O
Olympics	O
are	O
good	O
for	O
snowboarding	O
,	O
but	O
I	O
do	O
n't	O
think	O
this	O
whole	O
deal	O
is	O
,	O
''	O
he	O
said	O
.	O

``	O
Marijuana	O
is	O
not	O
a	O
performance-enhancing	O
drug	O
,	O
and	O
Ross	B-PER
did	O
not	O
smoke	O
it	O
;	O
he	O
was	O
just	O
subjected	O
to	O
it	O
,	O
''	O
he	O
added	O
.	O

``	O
Marijuana	O
is	O
present	O
in	O
every	O
sport	O
.	O

If	O
it	O
happens	O
to	O
be	O
more	O
present	O
in	O
snowboarding	O
,	O
it	O
may	O
be	O
just	O
because	O
it	O
's	O
a	O
younger	O
generation	O
.	O

A	O
lot	O
of	O
us	O
do	O
not	O
smoke	O
it	O
,	O
but	O
I	O
'm	O
not	O
denying	O
that	O
a	O
lot	O
of	O
my	O
friends	O
do	O
.	O

You	O
're	O
not	O
going	O
to	O
change	O
a	O
friend	O
because	O
they	O
do	O
.	O
''	O

Michalchuck	B-PER
was	O
not	O
the	O
only	O
Canadian	O
to	O
take	O
an	O
activist	O
stance	O
.	O

``	O
In	O
the	O
spirit	O
of	O
snowboarders	O
,	O
we	O
're	O
not	O
going	O
to	O
sit	O
down	O
on	O
this	O
,	O
''	O
said	O
Mark	B-PER
Fawcett	I-PER
,	O
one	O
of	O
Rebagliati	B-PER
's	O
fellow	O
giant	O
-	O
slalom	O
riders	O
.	O

``	O
We	O
're	O
going	O
to	O
try	O
to	O
take	O
the	O
scar	O
and	O
put	O
it	O
back	O
on	O
the	O
IOC	B-ORG
.	O

To	O
come	O
right	O
back	O
at	O
them	O
.	O
''	O

Cara-Beth	B-PER
Burnside	I-PER
of	O
the	O
United	B-GPE
States	I-GPE
said	O
:	O
``	O
Everyone	O
was	O
furious	O
.	O

Everyone	O
was	O
,	O
like	O
,	O
Ross	B-PER
won	O
the	O
gold	O
,	O
no	O
matter	O
what	O
.	O

It	O
was	O
n't	O
anything	O
that	O
was	O
affecting	O
his	O
performance	O
.	O

I	O
mean	O
,	O
come	O
on	O
,	O
they	O
're	O
kicking	O
people	O
out	O
for	O
cough	O
medicine	O
.	O
''	O

Others	O
were	O
more	O
circumspect	O
.	O

``	O
Well	O
,	O
marijuana	O
is	O
on	O
the	O
list	O
,	O
''	O
said	O
Norwegian	B-GPE
Anne	B-PER
Molin	I-PER
Kongsgaard	I-PER
,	O
who	O
added	O
that	O
the	O
disqualification	O
was	O
``	O
very	O
sad	O
.	O
''	O

Some	O
riders	O
also	O
expressed	O
dismay	O
that	O
after	O
waiting	O
for	O
years	O
to	O
show	O
their	O
moves	O
in	O
the	O
Olympics	O
,	O
this	O
issue	O
was	O
now	O
much	O
more	O
interesting	O
to	O
the	O
world	O
than	O
whether	O
they	O
had	O
just	O
performed	O
a	O
McTwist	O
.	O

``	O
It	O
's	O
a	O
weird	O
day	O
,	O
''	O
said	O
the	O
Canadian	B-GPE
team	O
spokesman	O
,	O
Paul	B-PER
Rivard	I-PER
.	O

``	O
Because	O
the	O
riders	O
know	O
everybody	O
wants	O
to	O
talk	O
about	O
something	O
other	O
than	O
their	O
run	O
,	O
and	O
they	O
want	O
to	O
stay	O
focused	O
.	O
''	O

OPTIONAL	O
MATERIAL	O
FOLLOWS	O
)	O

The	O
rain	O
that	O
began	O
falling	O
just	O
before	O
the	O
start	O
of	O
the	O
women	O
's	O
qualifying	O
run	O
certainly	O
did	O
not	O
do	O
much	O
to	O
lighten	O
the	O
mood	O
.	O

Nor	O
did	O
the	O
Olympic	O
organizers	O
'	O
questionable	O
decision	O
to	O
allow	O
a	O
relatively	O
small	O
number	O
of	O
fans	O
access	O
to	O
the	O
area	O
bordering	O
the	O
halfpipe	O
.	O

The	O
bulk	O
of	O
the	O
several	O
thousand	O
fans	O
were	O
instead	O
relegated	O
to	O
a	O
field	O
far	O
down	O
the	O
slope	O
,	O
their	O
view	O
of	O
the	O
halfpipe	O
obstructed	O
by	O
television	O
booths	O
.	O

``	O
Usually	O
everybody	O
is	O
right	O
up	O
next	O
to	O
it	O
,	O
''	O
said	O
Adam	B-PER
Merriman	I-PER
of	O
Vail	B-GPE
,	O
Colo.	B-GPE
,	O
who	O
traveled	O
to	O
Japan	B-GPE
to	O
watch	O
his	O
girlfriend	O
,	O
Barrett	B-PER
Christy	I-PER
,	O
compete	O
in	O
the	O
halfpipe	O
.	O

``	O
But	O
then	O
usually	O
there	O
are	O
n't	O
this	O
many	O
television	O
cameras	O
or	O
people	O
around	O
,	O
either	O
.	O

So	O
I	O
guess	O
that	O
's	O
good	O
.	O
''	O

The	O
teen-age	O
and	O
twentysomething	O
Japanese	B-GPE
fans	O
who	O
lined	O
the	O
front	O
row	O
of	O
the	O
roped-off	O
field	O
did	O
not	O
seem	O
to	O
mind	O
their	O
poor	O
seats	O
.	O

Snowboarding	O
is	O
in	O
fashion	O
with	O
Japan	B-GPE
's	O
trend-conscious	O
youth	O
,	O
and	O
there	O
was	O
no	O
shortage	O
of	O
baggy	O
pants	O
,	O
Airwalk	O
boots	O
and	O
dyed	O
orange	O
hair	O
.	O

The	O
National	B-ORG
Endowment	I-ORG
for	I-ORG
the	I-ORG
Arts	I-ORG
has	O
been	O
described	O
as	O
embattled	O
for	O
so	O
long	O
that	O
it	O
now	O
probably	O
assumes	O
this	O
word	O
is	O
part	O
of	O
its	O
name	O
.	O

Since	O
1989	O
,	O
when	O
it	O
financed	O
exhibitions	O
that	O
included	O
the	O
infamous	O
photographs	O
by	O
Robert	B-PER
Mapplethorpe	I-PER
and	O
Andres	B-PER
Serrano	I-PER
defying	O
conventional	O
religious	O
beliefs	O
and	O
sexual	O
behavior	O
,	O
this	O
agency	O
has	O
been	O
hammered	O
by	O
politicians	O
and	O
pundits	O
eager	O
for	O
a	O
soapbox	O
from	O
which	O
they	O
can	O
bemoan	O
declining	O
national	O
values	O
and	O
inappropriate	O
uses	O
of	O
government	O
money	O
.	O

The	O
NEA	B-ORG
has	O
been	O
relentlessly	O
attacked	O
by	O
conservative	O
critics	O
who	O
believe	O
that	O
financing	O
a	O
broad	O
spectrum	O
of	O
American	B-GPE
artistic	O
activities	O
,	O
including	O
crafts	O
and	O
art	O
made	O
within	O
communities	O
that	O
do	O
not	O
feel	O
welcome	O
in	O
art	O
museums	O
,	O
is	O
emblematic	O
of	O
the	O
erosion	O
of	O
quality	O
and	O
ambition	O
in	O
an	O
increasingly	O
multicultural	O
,	O
relativistic	O
America	B-GPE
.	O

If	O
only	O
the	O
NEA	B-ORG
would	O
disappear	O
,	O
many	O
opponents	O
believe	O
,	O
the	O
free-market	O
system	O
would	O
do	O
its	O
thing	O
,	O
the	O
cream	O
would	O
rise	O
to	O
the	O
top	O
,	O
and	O
art	O
would	O
once	O
again	O
look	O
like	O
the	O
paintings	O
of	O
Richard	B-PER
Diebenkorn	I-PER
and	O
Claude	B-PER
Monet	I-PER
.	O

As	O
Bill	B-PER
Ivey	I-PER
,	O
nominated	O
by	O
the	O
White	B-ORG
House	I-ORG
to	O
be	O
the	O
next	O
chairman	O
of	O
the	O
NEA	B-ORG
,	O
awaits	O
confirmation	O
hearings	O
,	O
what	O
the	O
endowment	O
has	O
been	O
and	O
can	O
be	O
are	O
once	O
again	O
urgent	O
issues	O
.	O

If	O
the	O
NEA	B-ORG
disappears	O
,	O
the	O
pressure	O
on	O
the	O
art	O
world	O
to	O
see	O
itself	O
as	O
part	O
of	O
a	O
larger	O
American	B-GPE
picture	O
will	O
be	O
sharply	O
diminished	O
,	O
and	O
the	O
entire	O
fabric	O
of	O
American	B-GPE
art	O
will	O
be	O
weakened	O
.	O

The	O
endowment	O
is	O
the	O
only	O
agency	O
in	O
the	O
United	B-GPE
States	I-GPE
whose	O
mandate	O
is	O
to	O
build	O
and	O
maintain	O
an	O
arts	O
infrastructure	O
and	O
to	O
secure	O
the	O
place	O
of	O
the	O
artist	O
in	O
society	O
_	O
a	O
society	O
that	O
before	O
the	O
agency	O
was	O
founded	O
in	O
1965	O
was	O
reluctant	O
even	O
to	O
acknowledge	O
that	O
artists	O
were	O
real	O
Americans	O
.	O

It	O
is	O
the	O
only	O
agency	O
that	O
has	O
been	O
concerned	O
with	O
the	O
totality	O
of	O
American	B-GPE
art	O
,	O
including	O
difficult	O
and	O
experimental	O
work	O
that	O
challenges	O
mainstream	O
thinking	O
.	O

In	O
an	O
American	B-GPE
art	O
world	O
still	O
largely	O
identified	O
with	O
big	O
institutions	O
that	O
can	O
effortlessly	O
slide	O
into	O
insularity	O
and	O
rampant	O
self-interest	O
,	O
the	O
endowment	O
is	O
the	O
only	O
agency	O
whose	O
existence	O
argues	O
for	O
the	O
importance	O
of	O
art	O
to	O
the	O
creativity	O
and	O
dynamism	O
of	O
the	O
nation	O
.	O

Anyone	O
who	O
believes	O
the	O
endowment	O
can	O
be	O
excised	O
from	O
the	O
art	O
world	O
without	O
seriously	O
damaging	O
American	B-GPE
art	O
should	O
consider	O
the	O
repercussions	O
of	O
the	O
radical	O
changes	O
within	O
the	O
agency	O
in	O
January	O
1996	O
.	O

After	O
the	O
Christian	B-ORG
Right	I-ORG
campaigned	O
against	O
the	O
endowment	O
and	O
members	O
of	O
Congress	B-ORG
promised	O
to	O
vote	O
it	O
out	O
of	O
existence	O
,	O
appropriations	O
were	O
cut	O
from	O
$	O
162	O
million	O
in	O
1995	O
to	O
$	O
99	O
million	O
in	O
1996	O
.	O

Laying	O
off	O
roughly	O
45	O
percent	O
of	O
the	O
staff	O
meant	O
that	O
the	O
endowment	O
could	O
no	O
longer	O
deal	O
with	O
the	O
number	O
of	O
applications	O
it	O
had	O
been	O
receiving	O
each	O
year	O
in	O
disciplines	O
like	O
painting	O
,	O
sculpture	O
,	O
media	O
arts	O
and	O
photography	O
.	O

Individual	O
artists	O
'	O
grants	O
,	O
which	O
had	O
been	O
the	O
source	O
of	O
much	O
of	O
the	O
punitive	O
wrath	O
that	O
threatened	O
the	O
agency	O
's	O
existence	O
,	O
were	O
eliminated	O
.	O

The	O
endowment	O
now	O
awards	O
grants	O
in	O
only	O
four	O
general	O
categories	O
:	O
heritage	O
and	O
preservation	O
,	O
creation	O
and	O
presentation	O
,	O
education	O
and	O
access	O
,	O
planning	O
and	O
stabilization	O
.	O

This	O
restructuring	O
has	O
had	O
far-reaching	O
ramifications	O
.	O

Once	O
the	O
endowment	O
stopped	O
giving	O
grants	O
to	O
individuals	O
,	O
many	O
small	O
and	O
large	O
arts	O
institutions	O
stopped	O
exhibiting	O
any	O
living	O
artists	O
who	O
might	O
make	O
someone	O
,	O
somewhere	O
,	O
angry	O
,	O
and	O
who	O
were	O
not	O
widely	O
acclaimed	O
and	O
collected	O
.	O

After	O
the	O
endowment	O
was	O
publicly	O
excoriated	O
for	O
having	O
the	O
temerity	O
to	O
award	O
some	O
of	O
its	O
money	O
to	O
art	O
that	O
addressed	O
changing	O
views	O
of	O
gender	O
and	O
race	O
,	O
many	O
institutions	O
lost	O
the	O
will	O
to	O
show	O
any	O
art	O
that	O
was	O
rambunctious	O
or	O
edgy	O
.	O

When	O
the	O
agency	O
was	O
deprived	O
of	O
its	O
ability	O
to	O
accumulate	O
comprehensive	O
information	O
about	O
entire	O
disciplines	O
_	O
for	O
example	O
,	O
5,000	O
applications	O
in	O
painting	O
alone	O
were	O
received	O
each	O
year	O
_	O
arts	O
professionals	O
became	O
less	O
willing	O
to	O
take	O
responsibility	O
for	O
art	O
as	O
a	O
field	O
.	O

The	O
will	O
to	O
think	O
big	O
,	O
to	O
ask	O
uncomfortable	O
questions	O
and	O
to	O
test	O
informed	O
and	O
strongly	O
held	O
convictions	O
is	O
now	O
largely	O
absent	O
.	O

The	O
mission	O
of	O
the	O
endowment	O
was	O
conveyed	O
through	O
the	O
medium	O
of	O
public	O
financing	O
of	O
the	O
arts	O
,	O
with	O
which	O
the	O
endowment	O
remains	O
largely	O
synonymous	O
.	O

To	O
what	O
and	O
whom	O
it	O
awarded	O
grants	O
,	O
and	O
the	O
political	O
reception	O
of	O
these	O
grants	O
,	O
inevitably	O
influenced	O
how	O
state	O
agencies	O
used	O
their	O
money	O
and	O
how	O
these	O
agencies	O
were	O
treated	O
by	O
local	O
politicians	O
.	O

(	O
As	O
of	O
January	O
,	O
40	O
percent	O
of	O
the	O
endowment	O
's	O
funds	O
go	O
to	O
the	O
states	O
in	O
block	O
grants	O
,	O
as	O
opposed	O
to	O
20	O
percent	O
between	O
1975	O
and	O
1990	O
.	O
)	O

Not	O
only	O
does	O
the	O
endowment	O
now	O
have	O
much	O
less	O
money	O
to	O
give	O
,	O
but	O
the	O
very	O
idea	O
of	O
public	O
financing	O
of	O
the	O
arts	O
is	O
now	O
tainted	O
by	O
the	O
microscopic	O
scrutiny	O
by	O
Congress	B-ORG
and	O
the	O
news	O
media	O
and	O
by	O
the	O
specter	O
of	O
right-wing	O
intimidation	O
.	O

When	O
arts	O
professionals	O
who	O
came	O
of	O
age	O
after	O
1989	O
think	O
of	O
public	O
support	O
for	O
the	O
arts	O
,	O
they	O
do	O
not	O
think	O
of	O
the	O
endowment	O
's	O
1965	O
mandate	O
to	O
``	O
help	O
create	O
and	O
sustain	O
not	O
only	O
a	O
climate	O
encouraging	O
freedom	O
of	O
thought	O
,	O
imagination	O
and	O
inquiry	O
,	O
but	O
also	O
the	O
material	O
conditions	O
facilitating	O
the	O
release	O
of	O
this	O
creative	O
talent	O
.	O
''	O

For	O
an	O
entire	O
generation	O
,	O
private	O
sponsorship	O
is	O
the	O
only	O
option	O
.	O

Private	O
support	O
can	O
not	O
meet	O
this	O
mandate	O
.	O

The	O
difference	O
between	O
private	O
and	O
public	O
support	O
was	O
succinctly	O
defined	O
in	O
a	O
1995	O
report	O
to	O
the	O
President	O
's	O
Committee	B-ORG
on	I-ORG
the	I-ORG
Arts	I-ORG
and	I-ORG
the	I-ORG
Humanities	I-ORG
by	O
Alberta	B-PER
Arthurs	I-PER
,	O
then	O
director	O
of	O
the	O
arts	O
and	O
humanities	O
division	O
of	O
the	O
Rockefeller	B-ORG
Foundation	I-ORG
.	O

``	O
Private	O
foundations	O
,	O
corporate	O
and	O
family	O
foundations	O
,	O
''	O
she	O
wrote	O
,	O
``	O
do	O
their	O
funding	O
by	O
guidelines	O
and	O
goals	O
which	O
are	O
special	O
to	O
their	O
interests	O
and	O
institutional	O
purposes	O
;	O
they	O
fund	O
to	O
advance	O
their	O
corporate	O
ideas	O
.	O
''	O

In	O
contrast	O
,	O
Ms.	O
Arthurs	B-PER
continued	O
,	O
the	O
National	B-ORG
Endowment	I-ORG
for	I-ORG
the	I-ORG
Arts	I-ORG
and	O
the	O
National	B-ORG
Endowment	I-ORG
for	I-ORG
the	I-ORG
Humanities	I-ORG
(	O
a	O
more	O
scholarly	O
,	O
academically	O
oriented	O
agency	O
,	O
also	O
founded	O
in	O
1965	O
)	O
``	O
must	O
support	O
the	O
whole	O
,	O
the	O
diversity	O
and	O
debate	O
of	O
sectors	O
,	O
of	O
ideas	O
and	O
talents	O
,	O
across	O
the	O
democracy	O
.	O

...	O
They	O
reach	O
across	O
disciplines	O
;	O
they	O
mobilize	O
and	O
leverage	O
other	O
resources	O
.	O
''	O

In	O
``	O
The	O
Illusion	O
of	O
Private	O
Giving	O
,	O
''	O
in	O
The	O
Washington	B-ORG
Post	I-ORG
last	O
summer	O
,	O
Robert	B-PER
Storr	I-PER
,	O
a	O
widely	O
respected	O
curator	O
of	O
contemporary	O
art	O
at	O
the	O
Museum	O
of	O
Modern	O
Art	O
in	O
New	B-GPE
York	I-GPE
,	O
expressed	O
his	O
alarm	O
at	O
the	O
current	O
imbalance	O
.	O

``	O
My	O
work	O
,	O
''	O
he	O
wrote	O
,	O
``	O
has	O
taught	O
me	O
to	O
have	O
no	O
illusions	O
about	O
how	O
inadequate	O
private	O
giving	O
_	O
however	O
generous	O
and	O
at	O
whatever	O
level	O
_	O
is	O
to	O
the	O
great	O
demands	O
confronting	O
cultural	O
institutions	O
.	O
''	O

After	O
writing	O
about	O
the	O
ferocious	O
competition	O
for	O
funds	O
in	O
art	O
museums	O
and	O
the	O
increasing	O
difficulty	O
small	O
and	O
midsize	O
institutions	O
have	O
raising	O
private	O
money	O
,	O
he	O
concluded	O
:	O
``	O
There	O
are	O
no	O
substitutes	O
for	O
government	O
's	O
contribution	O
to	O
cultural	O
affairs	O
.	O

...	O
The	O
coalition	O
of	O
support	O
that	O
has	O
helped	O
the	O
arts	O
to	O
thrive	O
in	O
America	B-GPE
is	O
dangerously	O
out	O
of	O
kilter	O
.	O
''	O

It	O
is	O
important	O
to	O
keep	O
in	O
mind	O
that	O
there	O
is	O
no	O
model	O
for	O
private	O
support	O
in	O
the	O
United	B-GPE
States	I-GPE
that	O
indicates	O
that	O
it	O
,	O
by	O
itself	O
,	O
could	O
meet	O
the	O
demands	O
of	O
this	O
or	O
any	O
future	O
artistic	O
moment	O
.	O

Before	O
the	O
1960s	O
,	O
when	O
private	O
patrons	O
felt	O
little	O
or	O
no	O
pressure	O
to	O
consider	O
the	O
impact	O
on	O
art	O
of	O
public	O
money	O
,	O
art	O
was	O
a	O
significant	O
but	O
peripheral	O
activity	O
in	O
the	O
United	B-GPE
States	I-GPE
,	O
and	O
American	B-GPE
art	O
was	O
almost	O
entirely	O
unknown	O
abroad	O
.	O

The	O
market	O
system	O
ignored	O
exceptional	O
artists	O
earlier	O
in	O
the	O
century	O
,	O
including	O
many	O
African-Americans	O
,	O
and	O
it	O
still	O
gives	O
little	O
support	O
to	O
many	O
exceptional	O
artists	O
,	O
particularly	O
those	O
who	O
prefer	O
to	O
work	O
outside	O
galleries	O
and	O
museums	O
.	O

Furthermore	O
,	O
private	O
support	O
is	O
unreliable	O
.	O

Corporate	O
giving	O
,	O
which	O
has	O
been	O
so	O
crucial	O
to	O
the	O
development	O
of	O
art	O
institutions	O
and	O
blockbuster	O
exhibitions	O
,	O
decreased	O
between	O
1984	O
and	O
1994	O
;	O
its	O
willingness	O
to	O
support	O
difficult	O
contemporary	O
art	O
can	O
never	O
be	O
counted	O
on	O
.	O

To	O
get	O
a	O
sense	O
of	O
the	O
dangers	O
of	O
the	O
current	O
imbalance	O
between	O
public	O
and	O
private	O
support	O
,	O
look	O
at	O
what	O
has	O
happened	O
since	O
January	O
1996	O
.	O

Arts	O
organizations	O
and	O
museums	O
have	O
turned	O
more	O
to	O
private	O
foundations	O
,	O
many	O
of	O
which	O
have	O
been	O
awarding	O
large	O
sums	O
to	O
programs	O
that	O
encourage	O
arts	O
institutions	O
to	O
engage	O
audiences	O
outside	O
the	O
familiar	O
constituencies	O
of	O
these	O
institutions	O
.	O

At	O
the	O
same	O
time	O
,	O
museums	O
have	O
come	O
to	O
rely	O
on	O
corporations	O
more	O
than	O
ever	O
.	O

Indeed	O
,	O
most	O
big	O
museums	O
are	O
so	O
eager	O
to	O
attract	O
and	O
keep	O
wealthy	O
corporate	O
board	O
members	O
that	O
they	O
are	O
reluctant	O
to	O
do	O
anything	O
that	O
might	O
challenge	O
corporate	O
values	O
and	O
interests	O
.	O

So	O
even	O
as	O
museums	O
are	O
becoming	O
,	O
in	O
theory	O
,	O
more	O
democratic	O
,	O
they	O
are	O
looking	O
and	O
acting	O
more	O
corporate	O
.	O

What	O
is	O
now	O
largely	O
missing	O
from	O
the	O
contemporary	O
art	O
programming	O
of	O
the	B-ORG
Modern	I-ORG
,	O
the	O
Solomon	B-ORG
R.	I-ORG
Guggenheim	I-ORG
Museum	I-ORG
and	O
the	O
Whitney	B-ORG
Museum	I-ORG
of	I-ORG
American	I-ORG
art	I-ORG
_	O
not	O
to	O
speak	O
of	O
the	O
Metropolitan	B-ORG
Museum	I-ORG
of	I-ORG
Art	I-ORG
,	O
which	O
collects	O
contemporary	O
art	O
but	O
wants	O
no	O
part	O
of	O
the	O
engagement	O
with	O
contemporary	O
life	O
that	O
is	O
proof	O
of	O
a	O
genuine	O
commitment	O
to	O
it	O
_	O
is	O
respect	O
for	O
the	O
courage	O
and	O
imagination	O
of	O
living	O
artists	O
and	O
an	O
awareness	O
of	O
the	O
needs	O
of	O
the	O
field	O
,	O
two	O
defining	O
aspects	O
of	O
the	O
endowment	O
's	O
mission	O
.	O

The	O
widespread	O
institutional	O
fear	O
of	O
artists	O
and	O
of	O
conflict	O
,	O
combined	O
with	O
the	O
wish	O
to	O
please	O
all	O
present	O
and	O
future	O
members	O
and	O
donors	O
,	O
helps	O
explain	O
why	O
so	O
many	O
museums	O
have	O
come	O
to	O
seem	O
like	O
satellites	O
of	O
the	O
entertainment	O
industry	O
,	O
in	O
which	O
success	O
is	O
measured	O
by	O
popular	O
appeal	O
.	O

Clearly	O
,	O
private	O
support	O
,	O
however	O
visionary	O
,	O
can	O
not	O
persuade	O
museums	O
to	O
fight	O
for	O
ways	O
of	O
thinking	O
that	O
challenge	O
their	O
immediate	O
social	O
and	O
economic	O
interests	O
,	O
and	O
it	O
can	O
not	O
persuade	O
arts	O
professionals	O
to	O
consider	O
the	O
art	O
world	O
as	O
an	O
ecosystem	O
in	O
which	O
every	O
part	O
is	O
connected	O
.	O

Public	O
support	O
for	O
the	O
arts	O
is	O
also	O
limited	O
.	O

While	O
the	O
new	O
endowment	O
structure	O
is	O
responsive	O
to	O
art	O
that	O
fell	O
through	O
the	O
cracks	O
before	O
,	O
like	O
projects	O
designed	O
to	O
develop	O
art	O
programs	O
in	O
schools	O
,	O
hospitals	O
or	O
community	O
centers	O
,	O
the	O
new	O
categories	O
only	O
reward	O
art	O
that	O
promises	O
to	O
realize	O
some	O
kind	O
of	O
quantifiable	O
social	O
or	O
institutional	O
good	O
,	O
thereby	O
keeping	O
the	O
agency	O
out	O
of	O
trouble	O
.	O

They	O
do	O
not	O
allow	O
it	O
to	O
support	O
artists	O
who	O
want	O
to	O
explore	O
technology	O
,	O
or	O
their	O
own	O
psyches	O
,	O
or	O
the	O
relationship	O
between	O
the	O
earth	O
and	O
the	O
stars	O
.	O

Just	O
as	O
important	O
,	O
the	O
endowment	O
can	O
not	O
liberate	O
itself	O
from	O
self-censorship	O
.	O

In	O
1990	O
,	O
Congress	B-ORG
voted	O
to	O
allow	O
the	O
National	B-ORG
Council	I-ORG
for	I-ORG
the	I-ORG
Arts	I-ORG
,	O
the	O
endowment	O
's	O
advisory	O
committee	O
_	O
whose	O
members	O
are	O
political	O
appointees	O
_	O
for	O
the	O
first	O
time	O
to	O
reject	O
grants	O
recommended	O
by	O
peer	O
panels	O
composed	O
of	O
experts	O
.	O

Last	O
December	O
,	O
Congress	B-ORG
voted	O
to	O
include	O
six	O
of	O
its	O
own	O
members	O
on	O
the	O
council	O
;	O
there	O
were	O
none	O
before	O
.	O

Self-censorship	O
now	O
infects	O
the	O
peer-panel	O
selection	O
process	O
and	O
indeed	O
the	O
entire	O
endowment	O
system	O
.	O

It	O
also	O
infects	O
the	O
thinking	O
of	O
small	O
and	O
large	O
arts	O
organizations	O
across	O
the	O
country	O
.	O

For	O
the	O
health	O
of	O
American	B-GPE
art	O
,	O
this	O
weight	O
must	O
be	O
lifted	O
.	O

No	O
solution	O
is	O
possible	O
without	O
reinventing	O
the	O
very	O
American	B-GPE
partnership	O
of	O
private	O
and	O
public	O
support	O
for	O
the	O
arts	O
that	O
has	O
been	O
a	O
model	O
other	O
countries	O
have	O
envied	O
.	O

It	O
was	O
indispensable	O
to	O
the	O
flowering	O
of	O
American	B-GPE
art	O
in	O
the	O
1960s	O
and	O
to	O
the	O
emergence	O
of	O
that	O
art	O
as	O
a	O
force	O
on	O
the	O
international	O
scene	O
,	O
communicating	O
to	O
the	O
rest	O
of	O
the	O
world	B-GPE
that	O
American	B-GPE
culture	O
had	O
arrived	O
.	O

This	O
model	O
must	O
not	O
be	O
dismantled	O
.	O

The	O
endowment	O
can	O
continue	O
to	O
attend	O
to	O
infrastructure	O
.	O

It	O
can	O
convene	O
panels	O
in	O
which	O
arts	O
professionals	O
from	O
many	O
disciplines	O
and	O
corners	O
of	O
the	O
country	O
work	O
together	O
.	O

With	O
more	O
money	O
,	O
it	O
can	O
be	O
far	O
more	O
imaginative	O
in	O
the	O
ways	O
it	O
approaches	O
its	O
broad	O
and	O
democratic	O
mission	O
.	O

It	O
must	O
trust	O
artists	O
again	O
,	O
perhaps	O
by	O
commissioning	O
individual	O
and	O
also	O
teams	O
of	O
artists	O
_	O
including	O
controversial	O
ones	O
_	O
to	O
tour	O
the	O
country	O
and	O
speak	O
with	O
audiences	O
,	O
town-meeting	O
style	O
,	O
about	O
their	O
ideas	O
of	O
artists	O
and	O
art	O
.	O

The	O
endowment	O
can	O
work	O
to	O
bring	O
together	O
rich	O
patrons	O
,	O
whose	O
tastes	O
and	O
interests	O
are	O
so	O
instrumental	O
in	O
defining	O
private	O
support	O
,	O
with	O
arts	O
professionals	O
from	O
other	O
social	O
classes	O
who	O
may	O
have	O
very	O
different	O
ideas	O
about	O
what	O
art	O
is	O
and	O
who	O
it	O
is	O
for	O
.	O

All	O
these	O
interactions	O
should	O
be	O
considered	O
research	O
and	O
published	O
.	O

In	O
these	O
and	O
so	O
many	O
other	O
ways	O
,	O
the	O
endowment	O
could	O
help	O
define	O
as	O
well	O
as	O
support	O
the	O
manifold	O
meanings	O
and	O
possibilities	O
of	O
art	O
in	O
this	O
country	O
.	O

The	O
private	O
sector	O
could	O
establish	O
and	O
endow	O
a	O
private	O
agency	O
that	O
gives	O
grants	O
to	O
individual	O
artists	O
,	O
as	O
well	O
as	O
to	O
the	O
kinds	O
of	O
adventurous	O
and	O
experimental	O
projects	O
the	O
endowment	O
is	O
now	O
so	O
reluctant	O
to	O
support	O
.	O

This	O
agency	O
does	O
n't	O
have	O
to	O
be	O
on	O
the	O
East	O
Coast	O
;	O
it	O
could	O
be	O
based	O
in	O
Chicago	B-GPE
,	O
perhaps	O
,	O
or	O
in	O
Los	B-GPE
Angeles	I-GPE
or	O
Houston	B-GPE
.	O

It	O
could	O
give	O
grants	O
in	O
both	O
individual	O
disciplines	O
and	O
interdisciplinary	O
categories	O
.	O

Like	O
the	O
endowment	O
's	O
system	O
,	O
the	O
awards	O
could	O
be	O
made	O
by	O
peer	O
panels	O
of	O
eight	O
to	O
12	O
arts	O
professionals	O
from	O
across	O
the	O
country	O
,	O
or	O
it	O
could	O
invent	O
another	O
selection	O
system	O
.	O

These	O
public	O
and	O
private	O
agencies	O
would	O
always	O
be	O
aware	O
of	O
what	O
each	O
is	O
doing	O
and	O
join	O
forces	O
at	O
crucial	O
moments	O
_	O
at	O
international	O
exhibitions	O
,	O
for	O
example	O
,	O
when	O
American	B-GPE
artists	O
need	O
to	O
feel	O
that	O
their	O
country	O
is	O
behind	O
them	O
.	O

Now	O
is	O
the	O
time	O
for	O
the	O
private	O
sector	O
to	O
act	O
.	O

MEXICO	B-GPE
CITY	I-GPE
(	O
AP	B-ORG
)	O
_	O
Scion	O
of	O
a	O
gentleman	O
farmer	O
,	O
Vicente	B-PER
Fox	I-PER
made	O
good	O
in	O
the	O
corporate	O
world	O
and	O
then	O
left	O
it	O
all	O
to	O
transform	O
himself	O
into	O
a	O
politician	O
the	O
likes	O
of	O
which	O
Mexico	B-GPE
has	O
never	O
seen	O
.	O

On	O
Friday	O
he	O
became	O
Mexico	B-GPE
's	O
new	O
leader	O
,	O
the	O
first	O
in	O
the	O
country	O
's	O
history	O
to	O
peacefully	O
wrest	O
the	O
presidency	O
from	O
the	O
party	O
in	O
power	O
.	O

He	O
did	O
so	O
with	O
his	O
startling	O
presence	O
_	O
a	O
6-foot-5	O
rancher	O
in	O
cowboy	O
boots	O
.	O

With	O
his	O
charisma	O
_	O
his	O
ability	O
to	O
get	O
people	O
to	O
believe	O
in	O
him	O
is	O
legendary	O
.	O

With	O
his	O
persistence	O
_	O
his	O
tireless	O
campaign	O
began	O
early	O
in	O
his	O
predecessor	O
's	O
term	O
.	O

And	O
with	O
his	O
proposals	O
,	O
laid	O
out	O
in	O
simple	O
language	O
easily	O
understandable	O
to	O
the	O
humblest	O
of	O
Mexicans	B-GPE
:	O
more	O
education	O
,	O
more	O
loans	O
,	O
more	O
jobs	O
and	O
less	O
corruption	O
.	O

Fox	B-PER
,	O
58	O
,	O
draws	O
his	O
style	O
from	O
his	O
childhood	O
in	O
San	B-GPE
Cristobal	I-GPE
,	O
a	O
village	O
in	O
north-central	O
Guanajuato	B-GPE
state	O
that	O
grew	O
up	O
around	O
his	O
family	O
's	O
farming	O
businesses	O
.	O

Among	O
his	O
friends	O
,	O
he	O
saw	O
poverty	O
of	O
the	O
kind	O
most	O
Mexican	B-GPE
politicians	O
glimpse	O
only	O
from	O
the	O
window	O
of	O
a	O
passing	O
SUV	O
.	O

Among	O
his	O
family	O
,	O
he	O
saw	O
the	O
damage	O
that	O
bad	O
economic	O
policy	O
has	O
wrought	O
on	O
small	O
and	O
medium	O
businesses	O
.	O

And	O
from	O
a	O
college	O
professor	O
_	O
a	O
Jesuit	B-ORG
priest	O
_	O
he	O
understood	O
that	O
people	O
like	O
him	O
were	O
doing	O
nothing	O
to	O
change	O
any	O
of	O
that	O
.	O

Fox	B-PER
,	O
who	O
had	O
risen	O
from	O
soft	O
drink	O
deliveryman	O
to	O
president	O
of	O
Coca-Cola	B-ORG
Mexico	I-ORG
,	O
had	O
a	O
crisis	O
of	O
conscience	O
and	O
decided	O
in	O
mid-career	O
that	O
he	O
would	O
be	O
different	O
.	O

An	O
invitation	O
to	O
enter	O
politics	O
from	O
an	O
opposition	O
presidential	O
candidate	O
confirmed	O
his	O
decision	O
.	O

He	O
immediately	O
set	O
his	O
sights	O
on	O
the	O
presidency	O
,	O
starting	O
with	O
a	O
congressional	O
seat	O
in	O
1988	O
.	O

He	O
was	O
cheated	O
out	O
of	O
the	O
governor	O
's	O
office	O
in	O
1991	O
,	O
but	O
won	O
easily	O
the	O
next	O
time	O
around	O
in	O
1995	O
.	O

His	O
undeclared	O
presidential	O
campaign	O
had	O
already	O
begun	O
.	O

Touring	O
much	O
of	O
Mexico	B-GPE
and	O
much	O
of	O
the	O
world	O
in	O
what	O
could	O
be	O
Mexico	B-GPE
's	O
longest	O
campaign	O
ever	O
,	O
Fox	B-PER
drummed	O
up	O
investments	O
and	O
marketed	O
himself	O
like	O
the	O
soft	O
drink	O
he	O
once	O
transformed	O
into	O
the	O
national	O
leader	O
.	O

On	O
July	O
2	O
,	O
he	O
defeated	O
the	O
presidential	O
ruling-party	O
candidate	O
at	O
the	O
polls	O
,	O
a	O
victory	O
that	O
only	O
months	O
earlier	O
had	O
seemed	O
a	O
fantasy	O
.	O

As	O
he	O
takes	O
on	O
the	O
presidency	O
,	O
much	O
of	O
his	O
homespun	O
style	O
will	O
come	O
with	O
him	O
.	O

He	O
continues	O
to	O
wear	O
his	O
boots	O
and	O
giant	O
``	O
FOX	O
''	O
belt	O
buckle	O
,	O
and	O
hints	O
he	O
might	O
drop	O
the	O
coat	O
and	O
tie	O
for	O
most	O
presidential	O
appearances	O
.	O

And	O
as	O
he	O
milked	O
a	O
cow	O
and	O
strolled	O
through	O
broccoli	O
fields	O
last	O
weekend	O
,	O
the	O
image	O
he	O
presented	O
was	O
starkly	O
different	O
from	O
any	O
of	O
Mexico	B-GPE
's	O
previous	O
presidents	O
:	O
a	O
normal	O
joe	O
,	O
a	O
bit	O
brighter	O
than	O
most	O
,	O
who	O
just	O
happened	O
to	O
have	O
won	O
the	O
presidency	O
.	O

Suffice	O
it	O
to	O
say	O
that	O
fine	O
minds	O
differ	O
.	O

Following	O
are	O
excerpts	O
from	O
the	O
note	O
written	O
by	O
Lt.	O
Dmitry	B-PER
Kolesnikov	I-PER
,	O
who	O
died	O
in	O
the	O
sunken	O
nuclear	O
submarine	O
Kursk	O
.	O

The	O
full	O
contents	O
of	O
the	O
note	O
have	O
not	O
been	O
released	O
,	O
and	O
officials	O
say	O
it	O
contains	O
lines	O
written	O
to	O
Kolesnikov	B-PER
's	O
family	O
that	O
will	O
not	O
be	O
made	O
public	O
.	O

The	O
following	O
lines	O
were	O
displayed	O
in	O
a	O
black	O
frame	O
next	O
to	O
Kolesnikov	B-PER
's	O
flag-draped	O
coffin	O
at	O
his	O
funeral	O
Thursday	O
:	O

''	O
15:45	O
.	O

It	O
's	O
too	O
dark	O
to	O
write	O
,	O
but	O
I	O
'll	O
try	O
by	O
touch	O
.	O

It	O
seems	O
there	O
is	O
no	O
chance	O
,	O
10-20	O
percent	O
.	O

We	O
hope	O
that	O
at	O
least	O
someone	O
will	O
read	O
this	O
.	O

``	O
Here	O
are	O
lists	O
of	O
the	O
personnel	O
of	O
the	O
compartments	O
who	O
are	O
in	O
the	O
ninth	O
(	O
compartment	O
)	O
and	O
will	O
try	O
to	O
get	O
out	O
.	O

``	O
Hi	O
to	O
everyone	O
.	O

Must	O
n't	O
despair	O
.	O
''	O

Navy	B-ORG
chief	O
Adm.	O
Vladimir	B-PER
Kuroyedov	I-PER
read	O
these	O
excerpts	O
to	O
journalists	O
on	O
Oct.	O
26	O
:	O

None	O
of	O
us	O
can	O
get	O
to	O
the	O
surface	O
.	O
''	O

The	O
Russian	B-GPE
Mafia	O
has	O
established	O
a	O
stronghold	O
in	O
Switzerland	B-GPE
,	O
using	O
the	O
Alpine	O
country	O
as	O
a	O
base	O
for	O
drugs	O
and	O
arms	O
deals	O
and	O
money	O
laundering	O
,	O
an	O
official	O
report	O
said	O
Friday	O
.	O

Without	O
rapid	O
action	O
,	O
there	O
was	O
a	O
risk	O
of	O
the	O
Swiss	B-GPE
economy	O
being	O
infiltrated	O
by	O
organized	O
crime	O
,	O
the	O
report	O
by	O
the	O
Swiss	B-GPE
Federal	B-ORG
Police	I-ORG
Office	I-ORG
said	O
.	O

It	O
said	O
90	O
companies	O
based	O
in	O
Switzerland	B-GPE
were	O
suspected	O
of	O
criminal	O
activities	O
in	O
connection	O
with	O
the	O
Russian	B-GPE
Mafia	O
.	O

''	O
This	O
is	O
only	O
the	O
top	O
of	O
the	O
iceberg	O
,	O
''	O
said	O
the	O
report	O
.	O

Switzerland	B-GPE
's	O
decentralized	O
legal	O
system	O
and	O
lack	O
of	O
investigators	O
to	O
fight	O
organized	O
crime	O
meant	O
the	O
true	O
scale	O
of	O
the	O
problem	O
was	O
much	O
bigger	O
,	O
it	O
pointed	O
out	O
.	O

Even	O
though	O
Switzerland	B-GPE
has	O
relaxed	O
its	O
legendary	O
bank	O
secrecy	O
and	O
tightened	O
money	O
laundering	O
laws	O
,	O
the	O
country	O
still	O
remains	O
a	O
popular	O
destination	O
for	O
criminal	O
money	O
.	O

Its	O
efforts	O
to	O
clamp	O
down	O
on	O
Russian	B-GPE
Mafia	O
activity	O
were	O
dealt	O
a	O
blow	O
late	O
last	O
year	O
when	O
a	O
Geneva	B-GPE
court	O
acquitted	O
a	O
suspected	O
Russian	B-GPE
Mafia	O
boss	O
,	O
Sergei	B-PER
Mikhailov	I-PER
,	O
of	O
charges	O
that	O
he	O
belonged	O
to	O
a	O
criminal	O
organization	O
.	O

The	O
court	O
cited	O
insufficient	O
evidence	O
.	O

Many	O
law	O
enforcers	O
fear	O
this	O
may	O
have	O
sent	O
a	O
green	O
light	O
to	O
other	O
criminals	O
.	O

The	O
police	O
report	O
said	O
that	O
smaller	O
Russian	B-GPE
firms	O
used	O
Switzerland	B-GPE
as	O
a	O
base	O
for	O
drug	O
and	O
arms	O
deals	O
,	O
whilst	O
the	O
bigger	O
companies	O
used	O
it	O
for	O
sophisticated	O
money	O
laundering	O
through	O
offshore	O
firms	O
with	O
bases	O
in	O
Switzerland	B-GPE
.	O

The	O
bigger	O
companies	O
all	O
had	O
good	O
contacts	O
with	O
important	O
political	O
and	O
economic	O
players	O
and	O
exploited	O
their	O
influence	O
,	O
it	O
said	O
.	O

The	O
report	O
said	O
that	O
prostitution	O
from	O
eastern	B-GPE
European	I-GPE
nations	O
,	O
which	O
is	O
also	O
run	O
by	O
organized	O
crime	O
,	O
was	O
on	O
the	O
increase	O
.	O

A	O
deputy	O
director	O
of	O
a	O
shoe	O
factory	O
in	O
Moscow	B-GPE
was	O
shot	O
and	O
killed	O
Tuesday	O
in	O
an	O
apparent	O
contract	O
killing	O
,	O
a	O
police	O
official	O
said	O
.	O

The	O
executive	O
at	O
the	O
Paris	B-ORG
Commune	I-ORG
shoe	O
factory	O
was	O
shot	O
twice	O
in	O
the	O
head	O
on	O
the	O
stairway	O
of	O
his	O
apartment	O
building	O
in	O
Moscow	B-GPE
,	O
according	O
to	O
a	O
spokesman	O
for	O
the	O
Moscow	B-GPE
police	O
who	O
declined	O
to	O
give	O
his	O
name	O
.	O

Witnesses	O
said	O
two	O
unknown	O
gunmen	O
shot	O
the	O
man	O
,	O
the	O
spokesman	O
said	O
.	O

He	O
said	O
the	O
victim	O
was	O
identified	O
by	O
police	O
at	O
the	O
scene	O
,	O
but	O
his	O
name	O
was	O
not	O
released	O
to	O
the	O
public	O
.	O

Scores	O
of	O
contract	O
murders	O
are	O
committed	O
every	O
year	O
in	O
Russia	B-GPE
.	O

Rivalries	O
between	O
competing	O
firms	O
and	O
conflicts	O
with	O
organized	O
crime	O
groups	O
can	O
lead	O
to	O
the	O
murders	O
,	O
police	O
have	O
said	O
.	O

A	O
former	O
Soviet	B-GPE
screenwriter	O
and	O
film	O
director	O
who	O
wrote	O
two	O
books	O
since	O
emigrating	O
to	O
the	O
United	B-GPE
States	I-GPE
in	O
1972	O
was	O
found	O
shot	O
to	O
death	O
Monday	O
in	O
his	O
Manhattan	B-GPE
apartment	O
.	O

The	O
victim	O
,	O
Yuri	B-PER
Brokhin	I-PER
,	O
48	O
years	O
old	O
,	O
had	O
been	O
shot	O
once	O
above	O
the	O
right	O
ear	O
.	O

There	O
was	O
was	O
about	O
$	O
15,000	O
in	O
cash	O
in	O
the	O
apartment	O
,	O
the	O
police	O
said	O
.	O

The	O
body	O
was	O
found	O
by	O
a	O
friend	O
,	O
Tina	B-PER
Ragsdale	I-PER
,	O
26	O
,	O
on	O
the	O
bed	O
in	O
the	O
one-bedroom	O
apartment	O
at	O
349	O
East	O
49th	O
Street	O
,	O
near	O
First	O
Avenue	O
.	O

No	O
weapon	O
was	O
found	O
in	O
the	O
apartment	O
and	O
there	O
was	O
no	O
sign	O
of	O
forced	O
entry	O
,	O
the	O
police	O
said	O
.	O

They	O
said	O
they	O
had	O
no	O
motive	O
for	O
the	O
shooting	O
.	O

Mr.	O
Brokhin	B-PER
's	O
first	O
book	O
was	O
''	O
Hustling	O
on	O
Gorky	O
Street	O
,	O
''	O
published	O
in	O
1975	O
by	O
Dial	B-ORG
Press	I-ORG
.	O

His	O
second	O
book	O
,	O
''	O
The	O
Big	O
Red	O
Machine	O
:	O
The	O
Rise	O
and	O
Fall	O
of	O
Soviet	O
Olympic	O
Champions	O
,	O
''	O
was	O
published	O
by	O
Random	B-ORG
House	I-ORG
in	O
1978	O
.	O

According	O
to	O
Dial	B-ORG
Press	I-ORG
,	O
Mr.	O
Brokhin	B-PER
had	O
worked	O
on	O
20	O
films	O
in	O
the	O
Soviet	B-GPE
Union	I-GPE
before	O
coming	O
to	O
this	O
country	O
.	O

WASHINGTON	B-GPE
(	O
AP	B-ORG
)	O
_	O
The	O
Yemeni	B-GPE
coastline	O
,	O
where	O
the	O
USS	O
Cole	O
met	O
disaster	O
in	O
an	O
apparent	O
terrorist	O
bombing	O
last	O
week	O
,	O
is	O
a	O
``	O
sieve	O
''	O
for	O
terrorists	O
but	O
was	O
the	O
best	O
option	O
available	O
for	O
refueling	O
Navy	B-ORG
ships	O
in	O
the	O
volatile	O
region	O
,	O
the	O
former	O
U.S.	B-GPE
military	O
commander	O
in	O
the	O
region	O
said	O
Thursday	O
.	O

``	O
I	O
pass	O
that	O
buck	O
on	O
to	O
nobody	O
,	O
''	O
Zinni	B-PER
told	O
a	O
Senate	B-ORG
Armed	B-ORG
Services	I-ORG
Committee	I-ORG
hearing	O
.	O

Zinni	B-PER
,	O
who	O
retired	O
earlier	O
this	O
year	O
,	O
said	O
he	O
and	O
the	O
rest	O
of	O
the	O
American	B-GPE
government	O
were	O
well	O
aware	O
that	O
terrorists	O
use	O
Yemen	B-GPE
as	O
a	O
transit	O
route	O
into	O
Saudi	B-GPE
Arabia	I-GPE
.	O

``	O
Their	O
coast	O
is	O
a	O
sieve	O
,	O
''	O
he	O
said	O
.	O

Yet	O
there	O
were	O
no	O
better	O
alternatives	O
and	O
Navy	B-ORG
ships	O
must	O
refuel	O
in	O
that	O
area	O
while	O
moving	O
to	O
and	O
from	O
the	O
Persian	O
Gulf	O
,	O
Zinni	B-PER
said	O
.	O

The	O
port	O
of	O
Djibouti	B-GPE
,	O
on	O
the	O
Horn	O
of	O
Africa	O
and	O
just	O
across	O
the	O
Gulf	O
of	O
Aden	O
from	O
Yemen	B-GPE
,	O
had	O
been	O
used	O
but	O
the	O
refueling	O
contract	O
there	O
was	O
terminated	O
in	O
about	O
1997	O
because	O
the	O
facilities	O
were	O
unsatisfactory	O
and	O
``	O
the	O
threat	O
conditions	O
were	O
far	O
worse	O
.	O
''	O

That	O
left	O
him	O
with	O
``	O
options	O
that	O
were	O
not	O
very	O
good	O
,	O
''	O
Zinni	B-PER
said	O
.	O

In	O
Russia	B-GPE
,	O
they	O
are	O
called	O
Vory	B-PER
v	I-PER
Zakone	I-PER
,	O
"	O
thieves-in-law	O
,	O
"	O
the	O
top	O
criminal	O
echelon	O
.	O

For	O
American	B-GPE
law-enforcement	O
agencies	O
,	O
they	O
are	O
a	O
new	O
threat	O
.	O

Jim	B-PER
E.	I-PER
Moody	I-PER
,	O
chief	O
of	O
the	O
Federal	B-ORG
Bureau	I-ORG
of	I-ORG
Investigation	I-ORG
's	O
organized-crime	O
section	O
,	O
said	O
an	O
ominous	O
sign	O
in	O
the	O
growth	O
of	O
Russian	B-GPE
underworld	O
activities	O
in	O
the	O
United	B-GPE
States	I-GPE
has	O
been	O
the	O
sightings	O
of	O
four	O
or	O
five	O
Vory	O
v	O
Zakone	O
.	O

The	O
highest-ranking	O
thief-in-law	O
to	O
arrive	O
here	O
is	O
Vyacheslav	B-PER
Kirillovich	I-PER
Ivankov	I-PER
,	O
say	O
F.B.I.	B-ORG
and	O
other	O
law-enforcement	O
agencies	O
.	O

Russian	B-GPE
organized-crime	O
experts	O
estimate	O
that	O
there	O
are	O
about	O
800	O
Vory	B-PER
v	I-PER
Zakone	I-PER
in	O
the	O
world	O
,	O
Mr.	O
Moody	B-PER
said	O
.	O

"	O
They	O
are	O
the	O
closest	O
thing	O
the	O
Russians	B-GPE
have	O
to	O
being	O
a	O
made	O
guy	O
in	O
the	O
Cosa	B-ORG
Nostra	I-ORG
,	O
"	O
he	O
said	O
,	O
referring	O
to	O
the	O
full-fledged	O
members	O
of	O
American	B-GPE
Mafia	O
families	O
.	O

Tattoo	O
of	O
an	O
Eagle	O

The	O
Vory	B-PER
v	I-PER
Zakone	I-PER
are	O
not	O
necessarily	O
members	O
of	O
the	O
same	O
gang	O
but	O
,	O
say	O
Russian	B-GPE
law-enforcement	O
officials	O
,	O
belong	O
to	O
an	O
honored	O
category	O
of	O
criminals	O
who	O
are	O
empowered	O
to	O
resolve	O
disputes	O
among	O
gangsters	O
.	O

Mr.	O
Moody	B-PER
said	O
that	O
the	O
existence	O
of	O
the	O
Vory	B-PER
v	I-PER
Zakone	I-PER
was	O
believed	O
to	O
predate	O
the	O
Communist	B-PER
revolution	O
in	O
1917	O
and	O
that	O
all	O
members	O
were	O
recruited	O
while	O
in	O
prison	O
and	O
branded	O
with	O
a	O
tattoo	O
of	O
an	O
eagle	O
with	O
talons	O
,	O
usually	O
on	O
their	O
hands	O
.	O

"	O
They	O
had	O
sort	O
of	O
a	O
coronation	O
ceremony	O
in	O
prison	O
or	O
in	O
the	O
old	O
gulags	O
where	O
they	O
took	O
an	O
oath	O
never	O
to	O
work	O
and	O
never	O
to	O
cooperate	O
with	O
the	O
police	O
or	O
the	O
military	O
,	O
"	O
he	O
said	O
.	O

Mr.	O
Ivankov	B-PER
,	O
54	O
,	O
was	O
convicted	O
in	O
1982	O
in	O
Moscow	B-GPE
on	O
charges	O
of	O
robbery	O
,	O
possession	O
of	O
firearms	O
,	O
forgery	O
and	O
drug	O
trafficking	O
.	O

He	O
was	O
sentenced	O
to	O
14	O
years	O
in	O
prison	O
but	O
was	O
released	O
in	O
1991	O
,	O
five	O
years	O
early	O
.	O

He	O
is	O
believed	O
to	O
have	O
slipped	O
into	O
the	O
United	B-GPE
States	I-GPE
last	O
year	O
with	O
a	O
false	O
passport	O
.	O

He	O
has	O
been	O
seen	O
strolling	O
on	O
Emmons	O
Avenue	O
in	O
Sheepshead	O
Bay	O
,	O
Brooklyn	B-GPE
,	O
and	O
dining	O
at	O
the	O
Rasputin	B-ORG
,	O
a	O
nightclub	O
in	O
Brighton	O
Beach	O
,	O
Brooklyn	B-GPE
,	O
and	O
at	O
the	O
Russian	B-ORG
Samovar	I-ORG
,	O
a	O
midtown	O
Manhattan	O
restaurant	O
,	O
said	O
detectives	O
with	O
the	O
New	B-GPE
York	I-GPE
City	I-GPE
Police	B-ORG
Department	I-ORG
.	O

Problem	O
of	O
Unfamiliarity	O

Maj.	O
Aleksandr	B-PER
Y.	I-PER
Sirotkin	I-PER
of	O
the	O
Russian	B-GPE
Ministry	B-ORG
of	I-ORG
Interior	I-ORG
,	O
who	O
worked	O
on	O
the	O
Ivankov	B-PER
case	O
,	O
said	O
in	O
an	O
interview	O
in	O
Moscow	B-GPE
that	O
Mr.	O
Ivankov	B-PER
's	O
emergence	O
in	O
America	B-GPE
was	O
"	O
terrifying	O
because	O
his	O
presence	O
in	O
the	O
states	O
will	O
implant	O
a	O
new	O
kind	O
of	O
criminal	O
ideology	O
that	O
will	O
give	O
birth	O
to	O
crimes	O
characteristic	O
of	O
Russian	B-GPE
criminals	O
.	O
"	O

Major	O
Sirotkin	B-PER
warned	O
that	O
the	O
F.B.I.	B-ORG
would	O
have	O
trouble	O
uprooting	O
the	O
thieves-in-law	B-PER
because	O
the	O
bureau	O
is	O
unfamiliar	O
with	O
the	O
group	O
's	O
ideology	O
and	O
culture	O
.	O
"	O

Ivankov	B-PER
is	O
a	O
smart	O
guy	O
with	O
great	O
life	O
experience	O
,	O
"	O
Major	O
Sirotkin	B-PER
said	O
.	O
"	O

He	O
is	O
not	O
likely	O
to	O
be	O
satisfied	O
with	O
a	O
minor	O
role	O
in	O
the	O
criminal	O
world	O
.	O
"	O

Federal	O
agencies	O
are	O
concerned	O
about	O
"	O
reports	O
that	O
Ivankov	B-PER
was	O
sent	O
over	O
to	O
coordinate	O
activities	O
between	O
gangsters	O
in	O
Russia	B-GPE
and	O
all	O
of	O
North	B-GPE
America	I-GPE
,	O
"	O
said	O
Joel	B-PER
Campanella	I-PER
,	O
an	O
intelligence	O
agent	O
with	O
the	O
United	B-ORG
States	I-ORG
Customs	I-ORG
Service	I-ORG
assigned	O
to	O
Russian	B-GPE
organized-crime	O
investigations	O
.	O

MALAYSIA	B-GPE
'S	O
aggressive	O
move	O
into	O
the	O
information	O
age	O
could	O
not	O
come	O
in	O
a	O
more	O
opportune	O
time	O
.	O

With	O
the	O
convergence	O
of	O
communications	O
and	O
information	O
technologies	O
(	O
IT	O
)	O
coupled	O
with	O
the	O
coming	O
of	O
age	O
for	O
the	O
Internet	O
and	O
its	O
related	O
technologies	O
,	O
the	O
stage	O
is	O
set	O
for	O
Malaysians	O
to	O
seize	O
the	O
chance	O
to	O
transform	O
into	O
a	O
knowledge	O
society	O
and	O
become	O
worthy	O
opponents/players	O
in	O
the	O
global	O
market	O
space	O
.	O

The	O
Internet	O
,	O
the	O
global	O
network	O
of	O
computers	O
,	O
is	O
now	O
far	O
reaching	O
into	O
the	O
country	O
-	O
extending	O
its	O
embrace	O
to	O
include	O
every	O
nook	O
and	O
cranny	O
of	O
the	O
nation	O
-	O
opening	O
doors	O
to	O
not	O
only	O
a	O
diverse	O
range	O
of	O
information	O
sources	O
but	O
also	O
an	O
exhaustive	O
list	O
of	O
possibilities	O
to	O
create	O
new	O
applications	O
which	O
add	O
value	O
to	O
people	O
's	O
lives	O
.	O

In	O
the	O
business	O
world	O
,	O
the	O
Internet	O
-	O
through	O
intranet	O
and	O
extranet	O
solutions	O
-	O
has	O
become	O
an	O
invaluable	O
tool	O
for	O
companies	O
to	O
harness	O
so	O
as	O
to	O
gain	O
a	O
competitive	O
edge	O
.	O

The	O
solutions	O
are	O
also	O
vital	O
components	O
in	O
developing	O
the	O
borderless	O
marketing	O
flagship	O
application	O
which	O
is	O
a	O
vital	O
element	O
for	O
spearheading	O
the	O
development	O
of	O
the	O
Multimedia	O
Super	O
Corridor	O
(	O
MSC	O
)	O
project	O
.	O

The	O
application	O
will	O
create	O
the	O
necessary	O
framework	O
and	O
infrastructure	O
to	O
support	O
electronic	O
commerce	O
(	O
e-commerce	O
)	O
initiatives	O
in	O
the	O
country	O
.	O

However	O
,	O
it	O
is	O
important	O
to	O
note	O
that	O
installing	O
or	O
implementing	O
Internet	O
technologies	O
for	O
technology	O
's	O
sake	O
would	O
not	O
ensure	O
instant	O
success	O
.	O

For	O
e-commerce	O
to	O
flourish	O
with	O
full-blown	O
end-to-end	O
business	O
transactions	O
,	O
strategic	O
planning	O
which	O
incorporates	O
both	O
business	O
and	O
technology	O
plans	O
that	O
are	O
complementary	O
is	O
necessary	O
for	O
an	O
organisation	O
to	O
see	O
feasible	O
returns	O
on	O
investment	O
.	O

Intranets	O
,	O
through	O
the	O
use	O
of	O
Internet	O
technology	O
,	O
are	O
positioned	O
as	O
a	O
platform	O
for	O
companies	O
to	O
optimise	O
,	O
expand	O
and	O
transform	O
new	O
channels	O
of	O
business	O
.	O

When	O
strategically	O
implemented	O
,	O
an	O
intranet	O
solution	O
will	O
provide	O
the	O
ability	O
to	O
mediate	O
mission-critical	O
,	O
decision	O
support	O
functions	O
in	O
organisations	O
.	O

It	O
will	O
also	O
help	O
further	O
improve	O
communications	O
and	O
collaboration	O
at	O
all	O
levels	O
in	O
an	O
organisation	O
.	O

With	O
intranets	O
in	O
place	O
,	O
it	O
is	O
only	O
logical	O
for	O
organisations	O
to	O
respectively	O
link	O
the	O
network	O
to	O
other	O
companies	O
'	O
for	O
extended	O
business	O
purposes	O
through	O
extranets	O
.	O

While	O
this	O
will	O
enable	O
the	O
sharing	O
of	O
information	O
among	O
enterprises	O
,	O
security	O
issues	O
such	O
as	O
firewalls	O
and	O
encryption	O
as	O
well	O
as	O
access	O
and	O
control	O
procedures	O
,	O
and	O
the	O
trust	O
levels	O
that	O
enterprises	O
have	O
with	O
each	O
other	O
will	O
emerge	O
and	O
there	O
will	O
be	O
a	O
need	O
to	O
address	O
them	O
.	O

Other	O
than	O
usage	O
in	O
business	O
,	O
Internet	O
technology	O
is	O
also	O
beginning	O
to	O
infiltrate	O
the	O
lifestyle	O
domain	O
.	O

``	O
Smart	O
homes	O
''	O
have	O
emerged	O
bringing	O
a	O
wealth	O
of	O
information	O
and	O
entertainment	O
to	O
families	O
over	O
telecommunications	O
lines	O
.	O

The	O
art	O
of	O
socialising	O
is	O
also	O
experiencing	O
a	O
change	O
where	O
Net/virtual	O
relationships	O
are	O
fast	O
overtaking	O
or	O
becoming	O
parallel	O
with	O
the	O
normal	O
human	O
relationships	O
.	O

Whether	O
this	O
would	O
prove	O
positive	O
or	O
otherwise	O
towards	O
society	O
in	O
the	O
future	O
is	O
yet	O
to	O
be	O
seen	O
.	O

All	O
in	O
all	O
,	O
the	O
Internet	O
has	O
a	O
lot	O
to	O
offer	O
.	O

However	O
,	O
its	O
value	O
and	O
benefits	O
are	O
only	O
as	O
good	O
as	O
how	O
we	O
use	O
it	O
.	O

The	O
nation	O
's	O
census	O
director	O
,	O
after	O
fighting	O
with	O
Congress	B-ORG
for	O
two	O
years	O
over	O
how	O
to	O
conduct	O
the	O
next	O
population	O
count	O
,	O
announced	O
yesterday	O
she	O
is	O
quitting	O
,	O
leaving	O
unfilled	O
a	O
critical	O
leadership	O
position	O
as	O
the	O
nation	O
heads	O
into	O
the	O
2000	O
census	O
.	O

Martha	B-PER
Farnsworth	I-PER
Riche	I-PER
said	O
that	O
the	O
dispute	O
with	O
Republican	B-ORG
congressional	O
leaders	O
did	O
not	O
directly	O
lead	O
to	O
her	O
resignation	O
,	O
but	O
several	O
people	O
who	O
know	O
her	O
well	O
said	O
she	O
was	O
frustrated	O
by	O
the	O
political	O
battle	O
and	O
the	O
prospect	O
that	O
it	O
would	O
continue	O
for	O
another	O
two	O
years	O
.	O

"	O
This	O
is	O
going	O
to	O
be	O
a	O
brutal	O
fight	O
,	O
"	O
said	O
Rep.	O
Thomas	B-PER
C.	I-PER
Sawyer	I-PER
(	O
D	B-ORG
-	O
Ohio	B-GPE
)	O
,	O
who	O
has	O
been	O
closely	O
involved	O
in	O
the	O
census	O
and	O
is	O
among	O
those	O
who	O
believes	O
the	O
ongoing	O
debate	O
played	O
a	O
role	O
in	O
Riche	B-PER
's	O
departure	O
.	O

Replacing	O
Riche	B-PER
will	O
be	O
,	O
by	O
all	O
accounts	O
,	O
enormously	O
difficult	O
,	O
given	O
the	O
disagreement	O
over	O
the	O
census	O
that	O
divides	O
the	O
Clinton	B-PER
administration	O
and	O
the	O
Republican	B-ORG
leadership	O
in	O
Congress	B-ORG
,	O
whose	O
approval	O
is	O
necessary	O
for	O
Senate	B-ORG
confirmation	O
.	O

The	O
dispute	O
centers	O
on	O
a	O
technical	O
question	O
with	O
broad	O
political	O
repercussions	O
:	O
Republican	B-ORG
leaders	O
,	O
particularly	O
in	O
the	O
House	B-ORG
,	O
are	O
adamantly	O
opposed	O
to	O
the	O
administration	O
's	O
plan	O
to	O
combine	O
head	O
counts	O
with	O
statistical	O
estimates	O
to	O
arrive	O
at	O
a	O
national	O
population	O
count	O
.	O

Riche	B-PER
,	O
backed	O
by	O
a	O
National	B-ORG
Academy	I-ORG
of	I-ORG
Sciences	I-ORG
panel	O
,	O
has	O
argued	O
steadfastly	O
that	O
in	O
order	O
to	O
improve	O
its	O
accuracy	O
,	O
the	O
census	O
should	O
rely	O
more	O
than	O
ever	O
before	O
on	O
sampling	O
,	O
which	O
gathers	O
information	O
from	O
a	O
random	O
selection	O
of	O
households	O
and	O
then	O
uses	O
that	O
to	O
extrapolate	O
characteristics	O
for	O
a	O
larger	O
group	O
.	O

The	O
idea	O
is	O
to	O
get	O
a	O
better	O
gauge	O
for	O
accounting	O
for	O
millions	O
of	O
Americans	O
,	O
predominantly	O
poor	O
and	O
minorities	O
,	O
who	O
have	O
been	O
missed	O
when	O
the	O
government	O
has	O
relied	O
almost	O
exclusively	O
on	O
a	O
door-to-door	O
head	O
count	O
.	O

Sampling	O
,	O
because	O
it	O
would	O
increase	O
the	O
numbers	O
of	O
minorities	O
counted	O
in	O
the	O
census	O
,	O
is	O
generally	O
considered	O
likely	O
to	O
benefit	O
Democrats	O
more	O
than	O
Republicans	O
.	O

With	O
that	O
issue	O
unresolved	O
,	O
the	O
bureau	O
is	O
heading	O
into	O
the	O
final	O
planning	O
stages	O
for	O
the	O
2000	O
census	O
,	O
a	O
$	O
4	O
billion	O
effort	O
that	O
will	O
employ	O
300,000	O
people	O
.	O

Rep.	O
Dan	B-PER
Miller	I-PER
(	O
R	B-ORG
-	O
Fla.	B-GPE
)	O
,	O
who	O
heads	O
the	O
House	B-ORG
subcommittee	O
that	O
oversees	O
the	O
census	O
,	O
said	O
he	O
was	O
startled	O
by	O
Riche	B-PER
's	O
departure	O
.	O

"	O
I	O
have	O
expressed	O
my	O
concern	O
that	O
we	O
are	O
rapidly	O
headed	O
toward	O
a	O
failed	O
census	O
in	O
2000	O
,	O
"	O
he	O
said	O
in	O
a	O
statement	O
.	O
"	O

Riche	B-PER
's	O
sudden	O
departure	O
adds	O
to	O
my	O
anxiety	O
.	O

...	O
"	O

Riche	B-PER
said	O
yesterday	O
she	O
was	O
leaving	O
to	O
pursue	O
other	O
interests	O
,	O
including	O
writing	O
and	O
teaching	O
,	O
and	O
an	O
administration	O
source	O
said	O
she	O
had	O
been	O
offered	O
a	O
lecturing	O
position	O
at	O
Princeton	B-ORG
University	I-ORG
.	O

"	O
I	O
have	O
done	O
what	O
I	O
came	O
to	O
do	O
,	O
"	O
she	O
said	O
,	O
citing	O
improved	O
methods	O
of	O
collecting	O
and	O
managing	O
the	O
nation	O
's	O
statistical	O
system	O
.	O

She	O
said	O
she	O
had	O
not	O
made	O
a	O
commitment	O
to	O
the	O
administration	O
to	O
stay	O
through	O
the	O
2000	O
census	O
.	O

Riche	B-PER
has	O
in	O
the	O
past	O
expressed	O
her	O
frustration	O
that	O
the	O
controversy	O
over	O
sampling	O
had	O
forced	O
her	O
to	O
focus	O
most	O
of	O
her	O
attention	O
and	O
energy	O
on	O
the	O
2000	O
head	O
count	O
,	O
while	O
the	O
agency	O
is	O
also	O
responsible	O
for	O
numerous	O
other	O
projects	O
.	O

"	O
I	O
want	O
a	O
life	O
,	O
"	O
she	O
said	O
.	O
"	O

This	O
is	O
a	O
tough	O
job	O
.	O

I	O
ca	O
n't	O
tell	O
you	O
how	O
many	O
people	O
say	O
,	O
'	O
That	O
's	O
a	O
thankless	O
job	O
.	O
'	O

Why	O
would	O
somebody	O
want	O
to	O
stay	O
in	O
a	O
thankless	O
job	O
when	O
they	O
've	O
done	O
what	O
they	O
wanted	O
to	O
do	O
?	O
"	O

Riche	B-PER
,	O
58	O
,	O
an	O
economist	O
who	O
helped	O
found	O
American	B-ORG
Demographics	I-ORG
magazine	O
,	O
took	O
office	O
in	O
1994	O
,	O
the	O
day	O
before	O
the	O
electoral	O
victory	O
that	O
gave	O
the	O
Republican	B-ORG
Party	I-ORG
control	O
of	O
Congress	B-ORG
.	O

Others	O
say	O
Riche	B-PER
was	O
in	O
an	O
nearly	O
impossible	O
role	O
.	O

"	O
The	O
difficulty	O
in	O
that	O
position	O
is	O
being	O
stuck	O
between	O
the	O
scholarly	O
community	O
,	O
advising	O
her	O
how	O
to	O
take	O
a	O
good	O
census	O
,	O
and	O
the	O
political	O
community	O
,	O
reacting	O
to	O
political	O
forces	O
,	O
"	O
said	O
William	B-PER
O'Hare	I-PER
,	O
a	O
demographer	O
with	O
the	O
Annie	B-ORG
E.	I-ORG
Casey	I-ORG
Foundation	I-ORG
.	O

A	O
Commerce	B-ORG
Department	I-ORG
spokesman	O
said	O
the	O
administration	O
would	O
begin	O
the	O
process	O
of	O
appointing	O
an	O
acting	O
director	O
soon	O
and	O
then	O
search	O
for	O
a	O
permanent	O
replacement	O
.	O

However	O
,	O
several	O
congressional	O
sources	O
expressed	O
concern	O
that	O
replacing	O
Riche	B-PER
with	O
someone	O
who	O
meets	O
Republican	B-ORG
approval	O
could	O
be	O
difficult	O
,	O
because	O
any	O
nominee	O
's	O
position	O
on	O
sampling	O
could	O
emerge	O
as	O
a	O
litmus	O
test	O
.	O

It	O
is	O
unlikely	O
the	O
White	B-ORG
House	I-ORG
would	O
nominate	O
a	O
successor	O
who	O
did	O
not	O
support	O
sampling	O
,	O
and	O
equally	O
unlikely	O
Republican	B-ORG
leaders	O
would	O
look	O
favorably	O
on	O
such	O
a	O
candidate	O
.	O

That	O
raises	O
the	O
prospect	O
that	O
the	O
position	O
could	O
go	O
unfilled	O
for	O
a	O
long	O
period	O
,	O
even	O
as	O
the	O
Census	B-ORG
Bureau	I-ORG
conducts	O
its	O
rehearsal	O
of	O
the	O
census	O
this	O
spring	O
and	O
begins	O
final	O
preparations	O
for	O
the	O
2000	O
count	O
.	O

According	O
to	O
the	O
administration	O
's	O
plan	O
,	O
census	O
employees	O
would	O
attempt	O
to	O
collect	O
a	O
questionnaire	O
from	O
every	O
household	O
,	O
but	O
then	O
contact	O
a	O
statistically	O
representative	O
sample	O
of	O
people	O
who	O
failed	O
to	O
respond	O
.	O

The	O
results	O
of	O
that	O
sample	O
would	O
be	O
used	O
to	O
arrive	O
at	O
a	O
total	O
population	O
figure	O
and	O
the	O
race	O
,	O
income	O
and	O
other	O
characteristics	O
of	O
those	O
who	O
could	O
not	O
be	O
counted	O
directly	O
.	O

Republicans	O
,	O
particularly	O
those	O
in	O
the	O
House	B-ORG
,	O
have	O
maintained	O
that	O
such	O
a	O
process	O
is	O
subject	O
to	O
manipulation	O
,	O
less	O
accurate	O
than	O
a	O
traditional	O
head	O
count	O
and	O
unconstitutional	O
.	O

In	O
the	O
appropriations	O
bill	O
approved	O
late	O
last	O
year	O
,	O
Congress	B-ORG
allowed	O
the	O
bureau	O
to	O
test	O
sampling	O
this	O
spring	O
,	O
but	O
vowed	O
to	O
renew	O
the	O
fight	O
before	O
the	O
2000	O
census	O
.	O

BEIJING	B-GPE
,	O
Jan.	O
20	O
(	O
Tuesday	O
)	O
-	O

Secretary	O
of	O
Defense	B-ORG
William	B-PER
S.	I-PER
Cohen	I-PER
said	O
today	O
that	O
he	O
is	O
satisfied	O
Beijing	B-GPE
will	O
not	O
continue	O
sales	O
of	O
anti-ship	O
missiles	O
to	O
Iran	B-GPE
as	O
he	O
wrapped	O
up	O
a	O
four-day	O
visit	O
here	O
that	O
underscored	O
improving	O
Sino	B-GPE
-	O
American	B-GPE
military	O
ties	O
.	O

At	O
a	O
news	O
conference	O
before	O
departing	O
for	O
Tokyo	B-GPE
,	O
Cohen	B-PER
described	O
his	O
meetings	O
with	O
Chinese	B-GPE
officials	O
as	O
"	O
warm	O
and	O
productive	O
.	O
"	O

Most	O
notably	O
,	O
U.S.	B-GPE
officials	O
said	O
,	O
the	O
Chinese	B-GPE
military	O
granted	O
Cohen	B-PER
an	O
unprecedented	O
peek	O
at	O
a	O
heretofore	O
secret	O
air	O
defense	O
command	O
center	O
and	O
concluded	O
its	O
first	O
formal	O
agreement	O
with	O
the	O
Pentagon	B-ORG
--	O
a	O
protocol	O
designed	O
to	O
avert	O
clashes	O
or	O
accidents	O
at	O
sea	O
.	O

Cohen	B-PER
declined	O
,	O
however	O
,	O
to	O
say	O
explicitly	O
whether	O
Chinese	B-GPE
Defense	O
Minister	O
Chi	B-PER
Haotian	I-PER
had	O
agreed	O
to	O
cancel	O
any	O
existing	O
missile	O
deals	O
with	O
Iran	B-GPE
.	O

China	B-GPE
reportedly	O
has	O
sold	O
C-801	O
and	O
C-802	O
anti-ship	O
cruise	O
missiles	O
to	O
Iran	B-GPE
in	O
defiance	O
of	O
U.S.	B-GPE
concerns	O
that	O
they	O
could	O
threaten	O
Persian	O
Gulf	O
shipping	O
,	O
and	O
it	O
remains	O
unclear	O
if	O
China	B-GPE
has	O
contracted	O
to	O
sell	O
Iran	B-GPE
any	O
additional	O
missiles	O
.	O

Nevertheless	O
,	O
Cohen	B-PER
's	O
sojourn	O
here	O
highlighted	O
significant	O
advances	O
in	O
one	O
of	O
Washington	B-GPE
's	O
most	O
sensitive	O
military	O
relationships	O
--	O
between	O
the	O
world	O
's	O
most	O
powerful	O
country	O
and	O
its	O
most	O
populous	O
one	O
.	O

Less	O
than	O
two	O
years	O
ago	O
,	O
a	O
U.S.	B-GPE
aircraft	O
carrier	O
battle	O
group	O
was	O
facing	O
off	O
against	O
Chinese	B-GPE
forces	O
on	O
military	O
exercises	O
near	O
the	O
Strait	O
of	O
Taiwan	O
,	O
and	O
tensions	O
were	O
high	O
in	O
both	O
capitals	O
.	O

Since	O
then	O
,	O
U.S.	B-GPE
and	O
Chinese	B-GPE
officials	O
have	O
labored	O
to	O
improve	O
ties	O
despite	O
domestic	O
opposition	O
,	O
lingering	O
mistrust	O
and	O
strong	O
disagreement	O
over	O
Taiwan	B-GPE
--	O
an	O
island	O
state	O
of	O
21	O
million	O
people	O
that	O
China	B-GPE
considers	O
a	O
rogue	O
province	O
and	O
the	O
United	B-GPE
States	I-GPE
is	O
legally	O
bound	O
to	O
support	O
.	O

Cohen	B-PER
's	O
visit	O
here	O
--	O
the	O
fifth	O
leg	O
of	O
a	O
seven-nation	O
tour	O
of	O
East	O
Asia	O
--	O
has	O
built	O
on	O
a	O
groundswell	O
of	O
good	O
feelings	O
engendered	O
by	O
the	O
October	O
meeting	O
in	O
Washington	B-GPE
between	O
President	O
Clinton	B-PER
and	O
Chinese	B-GPE
President	O
Jiang	B-PER
Zemin	I-PER
.	O

At	O
his	O
news	O
conference	O
,	O
Cohen	B-PER
held	O
out	O
the	O
prospect	O
that	O
the	O
U.S.	B-GPE
embargo	O
on	O
military	O
sales	O
to	O
China	B-GPE
might	O
someday	O
be	O
lifted	O
--	O
an	O
embargo	O
imposed	O
in	O
1989	O
,	O
following	O
China	B-GPE
's	O
bloody	O
crackdown	O
on	O
student-led	O
democracy	O
demonstrations	O
in	O
Beijing	B-GPE
.	O

He	O
said	O
the	O
Chinese	O
had	O
asked	O
to	O
buy	O
spare	O
parts	O
for	O
unarmed	O
U.S.	B-GPE
-	O
built	O
Blackhawk	O
helicopters	O
purchased	O
in	O
the	O
mid-1980s	O
.	O

On	O
Monday	O
,	O
Cohen	B-PER
tried	O
to	O
calm	O
Chinese	B-GPE
concerns	O
that	O
strengthened	O
U.S.	B-GPE
defense	O
ties	O
with	O
Japan	B-GPE
,	O
Australia	B-GPE
and	O
,	O
recently	O
,	O
the	O
Philippines	B-GPE
and	O
Singapore	B-GPE
may	O
be	O
designed	O
to	O
contain	O
China	B-GPE
.	O
"	O

Today	O
,	O
China	B-GPE
is	O
an	O
Asian	B-GPE
power	O
and	O
rightfully	O
so	O
,	O
"	O
he	O
told	O
an	O
audience	O
at	O
the	O
Academy	B-ORG
of	I-ORG
Military	I-ORG
Science	I-ORG
.	O
"	O

The	O
United	B-GPE
States	I-GPE
does	O
not	O
fear	O
this	O
,	O
nor	O
do	O
we	O
view	O
China	B-GPE
as	O
an	O
adversary	O
.	O
"	O

Defense	O
Minister	O
Chi	B-PER
responded	O
that	O
the	O
United	B-GPE
States	I-GPE
also	O
should	O
not	O
fear	O
China	B-GPE
's	O
push	O
to	O
become	O
a	O
regional	O
power	O
.	O
"	O

It	O
is	O
groundless	O
to	O
describe	O
the	O
modernization	O
drive	O
of	O
China	B-GPE
's	O
army	O
,	O
which	O
is	O
for	O
the	O
sake	O
of	O
the	O
country	O
's	O
economic	O
construction	O
and	O
of	O
a	O
defensive	O
nature	O
,	O
as	O
an	O
unstable	O
factor	O
in	O
the	O
region	O
,	O
"	O
he	O
said	O
.	O

U.S.	B-GPE
officials	O
noted	O
also	O
that	O
China	B-GPE
has	O
begun	O
sharing	O
some	O
information	O
on	O
events	O
in	O
North	B-GPE
Korea	I-GPE
,	O
where	O
a	O
food	O
shortage	O
and	O
an	O
unpredictable	O
Communist	O
regime	O
have	O
combined	O
to	O
raise	O
fears	O
for	O
the	O
stability	O
of	O
the	O
Korean	B-GPE
peninsula	O
.	O

Military	O
contacts	O
between	O
the	O
two	O
nations	O
,	O
nearly	O
nonexistent	O
in	O
1996	O
,	O
have	O
ballooned	O
to	O
almost	O
weekly	O
visits	O
by	O
Chinese	B-GPE
officers	O
to	O
the	O
United	B-GPE
States	I-GPE
and	O
vice	O
versa	O
,	O
U.S.	B-GPE
officials	O
said	O
.	O

On	O
Monday	O
,	O
Chinese	B-GPE
army	O
chief	O
of	O
staff	O
Fu	B-PER
Quanyou	I-PER
invited	O
Gen.	O
Henry	B-PER
Shelton	I-PER
,	O
chairman	O
of	O
the	O
U.S.	B-ORG
Joint	I-ORG
Chiefs	I-ORG
of	I-ORG
Staff	I-ORG
,	O
to	O
China	B-GPE
later	O
this	O
year	O
.	O

Still	O
,	O
the	O
United	B-GPE
States	I-GPE
appears	O
more	O
eager	O
than	O
China	B-GPE
to	O
broaden	O
the	O
relationship	O
.	O

In	O
recent	O
months	O
,	O
U.S.	B-GPE
military	O
officials	O
have	O
suggested	O
a	O
number	O
of	O
initiatives	O
on	O
which	O
the	O
Chinese	O
have	O
either	O
failed	O
to	O
respond	O
or	O
have	O
watered	O
down	O
.	O

Among	O
other	O
things	O
,	O
U.S.	B-GPE
officials	O
have	O
asked	O
that	O
American	B-GPE
and	O
Chinese	B-GPE
pilots	O
be	O
allowed	O
to	O
exchange	O
visits	O
;	O
the	O
Americans	O
are	O
particularly	O
interested	O
in	O
flying	O
China	B-GPE
's	O
new	O
Russian	B-GPE
-	O
made	O
SU-27	O
fighter	O
jet	O
.	O

The	O
Chinese	O
have	O
balked	O
at	O
the	O
request	O
,	O
U.S.	B-GPE
officials	O
said	O
.	O

Cohen	B-PER
also	O
called	O
today	O
for	O
the	O
two	O
sides	O
to	O
visit	O
each	O
other	O
's	O
nuclear-weapons	O
sites	O
,	O
and	O
he	O
noted	O
that	O
the	O
Chinese	O
were	O
"	O
studying	O
"	O
the	O
request	O
.	O

Cohen	B-PER
's	O
visit	O
to	O
Beijing	B-GPE
's	O
Air	O
Defense	O
Command	O
Center	O
Monday	O
was	O
the	O
highlight	O
of	O
his	O
trip	O
.	O

Arranged	O
just	O
days	O
before	O
he	O
arrived	O
,	O
the	O
visit	O
gave	O
him	O
and	O
U.S.	B-GPE
military	O
experts	O
a	O
glance	O
into	O
the	O
heart	O
of	O
China	B-GPE
's	O
defense	O
structure	O
.	O

Cohen	B-PER
was	O
accompanied	O
by	O
14	O
other	O
U.S.	B-GPE
officials	O
,	O
including	O
Adam	O
.	O

Joseph	B-PER
W.	I-PER
Prueher	I-PER
,	O
commander	O
of	O
U.S.	B-GPE
Pacific	O
forces	O
.	O

The	O
eight-story	O
building	O
,	O
fashioned	O
Soviet	B-GPE
-	O
style	O
from	O
concrete	O
,	O
is	O
situated	O
in	O
southeastern	O
Beijing	O
behind	O
a	O
lightly	O
guarded	O
gate	O
,	O
according	O
to	O
a	O
U.S.	B-GPE
official	O
traveling	O
with	O
Cohen	B-PER
.	O

Commanded	O
by	O
a	O
lieutenant	O
general	O
,	O
the	O
center	O
is	O
responsible	O
for	O
defending	O
the	O
skies	O
in	O
a	O
200-mile	O
radius	O
around	O
China	B-GPE
's	O
capital	O
.	O

It	O
has	O
the	O
ability	O
to	O
coordinate	O
surface-to-air	O
missile	O
batteries	O
;	O
to	O
track	O
thousands	O
of	O
military	O
and	O
commercial	O
planes	O
in	O
the	O
region	O
daily	O
;	O
and	O
,	O
most	O
significantly	O
,	O
to	O
generate	O
an	O
integrated	O
response	O
to	O
a	O
potential	O
crisis	O
,	O
the	O
official	O
said	O
.	O

"	O
It	O
was	O
an	O
interesting	O
mixture	O
of	O
old	O
and	O
new	O
...	O
of	O
technology	O
from	O
the	O
late	O
1950s	O
and	O
early	O
1980s	O
,	O
"	O
the	O
official	O
said	O
.	O
"	O

Some	O
places	O
had	O
computers	O
with	O
large	O
displays	O
.	O

In	O
other	O
places	O
,	O
I	O
smelled	O
vacuum	O
tubes	O
"	O
--	O
electronic	O
components	O
that	O
preceded	O
transistors	O
.	O

One	O
of	O
the	O
murkiest	O
areas	O
of	O
China	B-GPE
's	O
military	O
scope	O
is	O
its	O
sales	O
of	O
components	O
of	O
weapons	O
of	O
mass	O
destruction	O
.	O

Last	O
week	O
,	O
Clinton	B-PER
certified	O
that	O
China	B-GPE
has	O
stopped	O
selling	O
nuclear-weapons-related	O
material	O
--	O
a	O
problem	O
that	O
bedeviled	O
U.S.	B-GPE
-	O
Chinese	B-GPE
relations	O
for	O
years	O
.	O

U.S.	B-GPE
officials	O
say	O
they	O
are	O
still	O
concerned	O
that	O
China	B-GPE
is	O
exporting	O
conventional	O
missiles	O
.	O

On	O
Monday	O
,	O
Cohen	B-PER
departed	O
from	O
the	O
advance	O
text	O
of	O
his	O
speech	O
at	O
the	O
military	O
academy	O
to	O
express	O
pleasure	O
that	O
Chi	B-PER
had	O
reiterated	O
assurances	O
that	O
missile	O
sales	O
to	O
Iran	B-GPE
had	O
been	O
halted	O
.	O

That	O
pledge	O
was	O
made	O
just	O
before	O
the	O
Washington	B-GPE
summit	O
meeting	O
,	O
but	O
Cohen	B-PER
said	O
on	O
his	O
arrival	O
in	O
Beijing	B-GPE
Saturday	O
that	O
he	O
intended	O
to	O
follow	O
up	O
on	O
the	O
matter	O
.	O

U.S.	B-GPE
officials	O
said	O
there	O
was	O
some	O
confusion	O
about	O
whether	O
China	B-GPE
would	O
fulfill	O
existing	O
missile	O
contracts	O
to	O
Iran	B-GPE
or	O
cancel	O
them	O
as	O
well	O
,	O
but	O
Cohen	B-PER
declared	O
:	O
"	O
I	O
believe	O
that	O
we	O
have	O
assurances	O
that	O
such	O
sales	O
will	O
not	O
continue	O
in	O
the	O
future	O
.	O
"	O

At	O
the	O
same	O
time	O
,	O
he	O
warned	O
that	O
any	O
disruption	O
of	O
the	O
flow	O
of	O
oil	O
from	O
the	O
Persian	O
Gulf	O
as	O
a	O
result	O
of	O
technology	O
provided	O
by	O
the	O
Chinese	O
would	O
have	O
"	O
a	O
damaging	O
effect	O
on	O
China	B-GPE
's	O
relations	O
with	O
many	O
countries	O
around	O
the	O
world	O
,	O
including	O
the	O
United	B-GPE
States	I-GPE
.	O
"	O

Wheeeere	O
's	O
Johnny	B-PER
?	O

In	O
the	O
distant	O
era	O
known	O
as	O
Watergate	O
,	O
it	O
was	O
Carson	B-PER
who	O
ruled	O
.	O

Such	O
was	O
his	O
cultural	O
authority	O
_	O
and	O
restrained	O
exercise	O
of	O
it	O
_	O
that	O
his	O
belated	O
inclusion	O
of	O
White	B-ORG
House	I-ORG
scandals	O
in	O
his	O
``	O
Tonight	O
''	O
show	O
monologue	O
was	O
the	O
certain	O
sign	O
that	O
Richard	B-PER
Nixon	I-PER
was	O
through	O
.	O

But	O
Carson	B-PER
is	O
retired	O
now	O
,	O
and	O
there	O
's	O
no	O
stronger	O
indication	O
of	O
how	O
much	O
the	O
world	O
has	O
changed	O
than	O
this	O
week	O
's	O
news	O
from	O
the	O
Center	B-ORG
for	I-ORG
Media	I-ORG
and	I-ORG
Public	I-ORG
Affairs	I-ORG
:	O
There	O
have	O
been	O
more	O
Leno	B-PER
and	O
Letterman	B-PER
gags	O
about	O
President	O
Clinton	B-PER
's	O
sex	O
life	O
,	O
an	O
average	O
of	O
16	O
per	O
show	O
per	O
night	O
,	O
than	O
on	O
any	O
other	O
topic	O
in	O
the	O
center	O
's	O
10-year	O
history	O
of	O
monologue	O
monitoring	O
.	O

They	O
're	O
so	O
tasteless	O
that	O
,	O
as	O
the	O
non-late-night	O
comedy	O
writer	O
Larry	B-PER
Gelbart	I-PER
puts	O
it	O
,	O
``	O
It	O
could	O
n't	O
have	O
been	O
this	O
bad	O
in	O
the	O
last	O
10	O
minutes	O
of	O
the	O
Roman	B-GPE
Empire	I-GPE
.	O
''	O

And	O
what	O
difference	O
has	O
all	O
the	O
gags	O
made	O
?	O

The	O
raunchier	O
they	O
are	O
_	O
and	O
the	O
raunchier	O
the	O
news	O
that	O
inspires	O
them	O
_	O
the	O
higher	O
Bill	B-PER
Clinton	I-PER
's	O
poll	O
numbers	O
.	O

Carson	B-PER
is	O
n't	O
the	O
only	O
essential	O
compass	O
we	O
've	O
lost	O
on	O
the	O
waves	O
of	O
dizzying	O
scandal	O
.	O

Sam	B-PER
Ervin	I-PER
,	O
the	O
trust-inspiring	O
chairman	O
of	O
the	O
Watergate	O
hearings	O
,	O
is	O
dead	O
,	O
and	O
Fred	B-PER
Thompson	I-PER
,	O
let	O
alone	O
Al	B-PER
D'Amato	I-PER
,	O
proved	O
no	O
reincarnation	O
.	O

Howard	B-PER
Baker	I-PER
,	O
the	O
senator	O
who	O
demanded	O
what	O
the	O
president	O
knew	O
and	O
when	O
he	O
knew	O
it	O
,	O
is	O
now	O
a	O
shill	O
for	O
the	O
tobacco	O
industry	O
.	O

Instead	O
of	O
the	O
apolitical	O
,	O
no-nonsense	O
Watergate	O
Judge	O
Sirica	B-PER
,	O
we	O
have	O
the	O
partisan	O
,	O
Malibu	B-GPE
-	O
bound	O
Judge	O
Starr	B-PER
.	O

For	O
all	O
the	O
hand-wringing	O
about	O
how	O
Clinton	B-PER
's	O
alleged	O
deeds	O
have	O
supposedly	O
debased	O
the	O
values	O
,	O
ethics	O
and	O
morals	O
of	O
the	O
nation	O
,	O
who	O
in	O
American	B-GPE
public	O
life	O
has	O
the	O
standing	O
to	O
lead	O
us	O
to	O
judgment	O
of	O
him	O
?	O

Not	O
the	O
celebrity	O
clergy	O
.	O

Billy	B-PER
Graham	I-PER
,	O
who	O
never	O
met	O
an	O
embattled	O
president	O
to	O
whom	O
he	O
did	O
not	O
grant	O
absolution	O
(	O
Richard	B-PER
Nixon	I-PER
included	O
)	O
,	O
turned	O
up	O
on	O
Thursday	O
to	O
embrace	O
Clinton	B-PER
at	O
the	O
National	O
Prayer	O
Breakfast	O
.	O

Jesse	B-PER
Jackson	I-PER
is	O
on	O
the	O
White	B-ORG
House	I-ORG
TV	O
spin	O
team	O
,	O
providing	O
reassuring	O
bulletins	O
from	O
phone	O
chats	O
he	O
's	O
had	O
with	O
the	O
first	O
daughter	O
in	O
Palo	B-GPE
Alto	I-GPE
.	O

Jerry	B-PER
Falwell	I-PER
is	O
a	O
peddler	O
of	O
crazy	O
,	O
hateful	O
videos	O
accusing	O
the	O
president	O
of	O
murder	O
.	O

That	O
oily	O
paragon	O
of	O
big	O
money	O
and	O
hypocritical	O
political	O
cynicism	O
,	O
Pat	B-PER
Robertson	I-PER
,	O
has	O
so	O
little	O
credibility	O
that	O
you	O
have	O
to	O
wonder	O
if	O
his	O
campaign	O
to	O
save	O
Karla	B-PER
Faye	I-PER
Tucker	I-PER
hastened	O
her	O
execution	O
.	O

The	O
press	O
?	O

The	O
many	O
retracted	O
Oralgate	O
stories	O
have	O
taken	O
their	O
toll	O
;	O
yesterday	O
's	O
Pew	B-ORG
poll	O
found	O
that	O
63	O
percent	O
of	O
the	O
public	O
dismisses	O
news	O
reports	O
as	O
``	O
often	O
inaccurate	O
.	O
''	O

The	O
fire-and-brimstone	O
broadcast	O
preachers	O
on	O
Presidential	O
morality	O
include	O
the	O
past-gate	O
scoundrels	O
G.	B-PER
Gordon	I-PER
Liddy	I-PER
and	O
Oliver	B-PER
North	I-PER
_	O
as	O
well	O
as	O
George	B-PER
Will	I-PER
,	O
whose	O
own	O
elastic	O
ethics	O
allowed	O
him	O
to	O
coach	O
Ronald	B-PER
Reagan	I-PER
for	O
a	O
1980	O
debate	O
while	O
keeping	O
his	O
role	O
a	O
secret	O
from	O
ABC	O
News	O
viewers	O
to	O
whom	O
he	O
then	O
effused	O
over	O
Reagan	B-PER
's	O
performance	O
.	O

Politicians	O
?	O

Very	O
few	O
have	O
been	O
heard	O
from	O
,	O
and	O
we	O
know	O
why	O
.	O

Newt	B-PER
Gingrich	I-PER
,	O
third	O
in	O
line	O
for	O
the	O
presidency	O
,	O
was	O
branded	O
with	O
the	O
scarlet	O
A	O
by	O
the	O
right-leaning	O
New	B-ORG
York	I-ORG
Post	I-ORG
three	O
years	O
ago	O
,	O
when	O
it	O
gave	O
its	O
front-page	O
imprimatur	O
to	O
allegations	O
that	O
he	O
``	O
made	O
whoopee	O
''	O
on	O
his	O
office	O
desk	O
.	O

Phil	B-PER
Gramm	I-PER
,	O
who	O
chastises	O
Clinton	B-PER
for	O
having	O
``	O
no	O
bearings	O
,	O
''	O
was	O
revealed	O
in	O
his	O
'96	O
Presidential	O
campaign	O
to	O
have	O
invested	O
in	O
a	O
soft-core	O
movie	O
called	O
``	O
Beauty	O
Queens	O
.	O
''	O

Some	O
of	O
the	O
sternest	O
Capitol	B-ORG
Hill	I-ORG
attacks	O
on	O
Clinton	B-PER
's	O
``	O
moral	O
fiber	O
''	O
have	O
come	O
from	O
none	O
other	O
than	O
Helen	B-PER
Chenoweth	I-PER
,	O
the	O
Idaho	B-GPE
congresswoman	O
who	O
publicly	O
fed	O
false	O
militia-spawned	O
rumors	O
of	O
malevolent	O
government	O
helicopters	O
in	O
the	O
months	O
before	O
the	O
Oklahoma	B-GPE
City	I-GPE
bombing	O
.	O

No	O
wonder	O
Ralph	B-PER
Reed	I-PER
has	O
now	O
advised	O
his	O
fellow	O
Republicans	B-PER
to	O
find	O
``	O
someone	O
who	O
is	O
beyond	O
reproach	O
personally	O
''	O
to	O
take	O
on	O
the	O
president	O
_	O
a	O
casting	O
call	O
that	O
has	O
had	O
few	O
takers	O
beyond	O
the	O
self-appointed	O
national	O
scold	O
William	B-PER
Bennett	I-PER
.	O

Nor	O
have	O
Democrats	B-PER
done	O
any	O
better	O
:	O
they	O
've	O
found	O
no	O
above-the-fray	O
leader	O
who	O
can	O
either	O
defend	O
or	O
disown	O
Clinton	B-PER
from	O
an	O
impartial	O
,	O
nonpartisan	O
moral	O
plane	O
.	O

So	O
far	O
only	O
Al	B-PER
Gore	I-PER
has	O
even	O
applied	O
.	O

Thus	O
does	O
the	O
fate	O
of	O
this	O
White	B-ORG
House	I-ORG
hang	O
,	O
incredibly	O
enough	O
,	O
on	O
the	O
American	B-GPE
people	O
,	O
who	O
so	O
far	O
seem	O
to	O
be	O
reserving	O
judgment	O
and	O
ignoring	O
the	O
pronouncements	O
of	O
press	O
,	O
clergy	O
,	O
politicians	O
and	O
late-night	O
comics	O
alike	O
.	O

Moral	O
fiber	O
aside	O
,	O
democracy	O
is	O
on	O
a	O
roll	O
.	O

MOSCOW	B-GPE
(	O
CNN	B-ORG
)	O
--	O
On	O
February	O
28	O
,	O
businessman	O
Victor	B-PER
Borisov	I-PER
traveled	O
down	O
a	O
packed	O
street	O
in	O
Taganka	O
Square	O
,	O
a	O
crowded	O
Moscow	B-GPE
commercial	O
district	O
.	O

People	O
lined	O
the	O
streets	O
,	O
rushing	O
to	O
and	O
from	O
work	O
.	O

As	O
Borisov	B-PER
's	O
driver	O
stopped	O
at	O
a	O
traffic	O
light	O
,	O
two	O
young	O
men	O
approached	O
the	O
black	O
Volga	B-ORG
sedan	O
and	O
peppered	O
the	O
interior	O
with	O
bullets	O
.	O

The	O
two	O
men	O
inside	O
died	O
instantly	O
,	O
and	O
the	O
men	O
who	O
fired	O
the	O
shots	O
sped	O
away	O
in	O
a	O
vehicle	O
parked	O
nearby	O
.	O

Police	O
say	O
Borisov	B-PER
and	O
his	O
chauffeur	O
were	O
victims	O
of	O
a	O
contract	O
killing	O
,	O
an	O
increasingly	O
popular	O
way	O
to	O
settle	O
scores	O
in	O
Russia	B-GPE
.	O

The	O
investigators	O
,	O
speaking	O
on	O
the	O
condition	O
of	O
anonymity	O
,	O
say	O
anyone	O
doing	O
business	O
in	O
Moscow	B-GPE
is	O
now	O
a	O
potential	O
mafia	O
target	O
.	O

Typically	O
,	O
the	O
businessmen	O
are	O
killed	O
by	O
the	O
Russian	B-GPE
mafia	O
because	O
they	O
can	O
not	O
pay	O
their	O
debts	O
,	O
or	O
they	O
refuse	O
to	O
pay	O
someone	O
off	O
.	O

As	O
happens	O
elsewhere	O
,	O
different	O
mafia	O
organizations	O
stake	O
out	O
certain	O
commercial	O
areas	O
to	O
control	O
.	O
"	O

Gangs	O
divide	O
spheres	O
of	O
influence	O
in	O
clashes	O
against	O
each	O
other	O
,	O
"	O
the	O
policeman	O
says	O
.	O

Depending	O
on	O
the	O
victim	O
,	O
hits	O
cost	O
anywhere	O
from	O
$	O
5,000	O
to	O
$	O
250,000	O
,	O
he	O
says	O
.	O

In	O
1995	O
,	O
4	O
percent	O
of	O
Russian	B-GPE
murders	O
were	O
attributed	O
to	O
contract	O
killings	O
,	O
and	O
officials	O
say	O
the	O
crime	O
is	O
on	O
the	O
rise	O
.	O

Perhaps	O
the	O
most	O
infamous	O
contract	O
killing	O
was	O
that	O
of	O
Vladimir	B-PER
Listyev	I-PER
,	O
a	O
popular	O
TV	O
talk	O
show	O
host	O
killed	O
in	O
his	O
doorway	O
--	O
a	O
favorite	O
spot	O
of	O
contract	O
killers	O
.	O

Infamous	O
contracts	O
Listyev	B-PER
,	O
like	O
Borisov	B-PER
,	O
seemed	O
an	O
unlikely	O
target	O
.	O

Friends	O
of	O
both	O
men	O
said	O
they	O
were	O
unaware	O
of	O
any	O
debts	O
or	O
affiliations	O
with	O
the	O
mafia	O
.	O

Thousands	O
mourned	O
Listyev	B-PER
's	O
death	O
;	O
he	O
was	O
known	O
as	O
an	O
honest	O
businessman	O
.	O

But	O
Moscow	B-GPE
police	O
told	O
CNN	B-ORG
Listyev	B-PER
may	O
have	O
dealt	O
with	O
dubious	O
partners	O
,	O
and	O
his	O
slaying	O
may	O
have	O
revolved	O
around	O
a	O
debt	O
,	O
regardless	O
of	O
what	O
his	O
friends	O
said	O
.	O

More	O
than	O
a	O
year	O
later	O
,	O
no	O
arrests	O
have	O
been	O
made	O
in	O
either	O
case	O
.	O

Police	O
say	O
they	O
are	O
thwarted	O
at	O
every	O
turn	O
;	O
they	O
are	O
outgunned	O
,	O
outmanned	O
and	O
outspent	O
by	O
their	O
mafia	O
foes	O
.	O

Also	O
,	O
Russia	B-GPE
's	O
criminal	O
code	O
does	O
n't	O
adequately	O
address	O
contract	O
killings	O
,	O
making	O
it	O
difficult	O
to	O
punish	O
those	O
who	O
order	O
the	O
murders	O
--	O
if	O
police	O
can	O
figure	O
out	O
who	O
they	O
are	O
.	O

"	O
Contract	O
killings	O
are	O
done	O
with	O
many	O
different	O
steps	O
,	O
and	O
it	O
's	O
possible	O
that	O
the	O
person	O
who	O
actually	O
committed	O
the	O
killing	O
can	O
only	O
be	O
found	O
under	O
some	O
asphalt	O
,	O
"	O
says	O
Lt.	O
Col.	O
Vladislav	B-PER
Karpovetz	I-PER
.	O
"	O

They	O
lay	O
down	O
some	O
asphalt	O
over	O
them	O
and	O
the	O
hire	O
ceases	O
to	O
exist	O
.	O
"	O

Meanwhile	O
,	O
as	O
the	O
killings	O
continue	O
,	O
many	O
Russian	B-GPE
businessmen	O
have	O
hired	O
bodyguards	O
.	O

But	O
,	O
not	O
even	O
they	O
are	O
immune	O
to	O
attack	O
.	O

One	O
bodyguard	O
died	O
in	O
a	O
hail	O
of	O
gunfire	O
at	O
the	O
Palace	O
Hotel	O
in	O
St.	B-GPE
Petersburg	I-GPE
,	O
along	O
with	O
his	O
boss	O
and	O
an	O
innocent	O
British	B-GPE
bystander	O
.	O

"	O
You	O
can	O
have	O
armed	O
bodyguards	O
and	O
an	O
armored	O
car	O
,	O
"	O
nightclub	O
owner	O
Vyacheslav	B-PER
Piskizhov	I-PER
says	O
.	O
"	O

But	O
if	O
they	O
want	O
--	O
as	O
it	O
goes	O
--	O
to	O
take	O
you	O
out	O
,	O
they	O
'll	O
take	O
you	O
out	O
along	O
with	O
your	O
bodyguard	O
.	O
"	O

From	O
CNN	B-ORG
Correspondent	O
Eileen	O
O'Connor	O

LONDON	B-GPE
,	O
Jan.	O
9	O
-	O

Threats	O
to	O
the	O
resumption	O
of	O
the	O
Northern	B-GPE
Ireland	I-GPE
peace	O
talks	O
receded	O
today	O
after	O
a	O
British	B-GPE
cabinet	O
minister	O
entered	O
the	O
huge	O
Maze	O
prison	O
near	O
Belfast	B-GPE
and	O
pressed	O
Protestant	B-ORG
guerrillas	O
held	O
there	O
to	O
support	O
continuing	O
the	O
discussions	O
.	O

Northern	B-GPE
Ireland	I-GPE
Secretary	O
Marjorie	B-PER
Mowlam	I-PER
sat	O
down	O
with	O
members	O
of	O
two	O
outlawed	O
Protestant	B-ORG
paramilitary	O
groups	O
and	O
delivered	O
a	O
14-point	O
statement	O
on	O
why	O
they	O
should	O
reverse	O
a	O
vote	O
they	O
took	O
last	O
weekend	O
to	O
condemn	O
the	O
talks	O
.	O

That	O
vote	O
had	O
thrown	O
the	O
talks	O
'	O
future	O
into	O
question	O
.	O

After	O
she	O
left	O
,	O
the	O
prisoners	O
did	O
what	O
she	O
asked	O
.	O

The	O
political	O
party	O
that	O
speaks	O
for	O
them	O
at	O
the	O
negotiating	O
table	O
,	O
the	O
Ulster	B-ORG
Democratic	I-ORG
Party	I-ORG
,	O
announced	O
it	O
was	O
no	O
longer	O
considering	O
boycotting	O
the	O
talks	O
,	O
which	O
are	O
set	O
to	O
resume	O
Monday	O
.	O

Another	O
party	O
affiliated	O
with	O
imprisoned	O
Protestant	B-ORG
guerrillas	O
,	O
the	O
Progressive	B-ORG
Unionist	I-ORG
Party	I-ORG
,	O
said	O
it	O
would	O
decide	O
on	O
Sunday	O
whether	O
to	O
attend	O
.	O

The	O
all-party	O
talks	O
,	O
chaired	O
by	O
former	O
U.S.	B-GPE
senator	O
George	B-PER
J.	I-PER
Mitchell	I-PER
(	O
D	B-ORG
-	O
Maine	B-GPE
)	O
,	O
seek	O
a	O
political	O
solution	O
in	O
Northern	B-GPE
Ireland	I-GPE
between	O
Protestants	O
,	O
most	O
of	O
whom	O
want	O
to	O
remain	O
part	O
of	O
Britain	B-GPE
,	O
and	O
Catholics	B-PER
,	O
who	O
want	O
greater	O
political	O
rights	O
,	O
including	O
,	O
for	O
some	O
,	O
political	O
union	O
with	O
the	O
Republic	B-GPE
of	I-GPE
Ireland	I-GPE
to	O
the	O
south	O
.	O

Throughout	O
the	O
conflict	O
,	O
the	O
British	B-GPE
government	O
has	O
held	O
to	O
the	O
line	O
that	O
it	O
talks	O
to	O
people	O
who	O
renounce	O
violence	O
,	O
not	O
to	O
killers	O
.	O

To	O
many	O
people	O
in	O
Britain	B-GPE
,	O
it	O
seemed	O
today	O
that	O
Mowlam	B-PER
was	O
being	O
summoned	O
by	O
men	O
convicted	O
of	O
crimes	O
that	O
include	O
murder	O
and	O
arson	O
.	O

"	O
We	O
are	O
very	O
unhappy	O
about	O
it	O
,	O
"	O
said	O
Glyn	B-PER
Roberts	I-PER
,	O
development	O
officer	O
for	O
a	O
Northern	B-GPE
Ireland	I-GPE
peace	O
group	O
called	O
Families	B-ORG
Against	I-ORG
Intimidation	I-ORG
and	I-ORG
Terror	I-ORG
.	O

Mowlam	B-PER
spoke	O
directly	O
with	O
terrorists	O
,	O
he	O
said	O
,	O
"	O
which	O
many	O
victims	O
felt	O
was	O
grossly	O
insulting	O
.	O
"	O

Addressing	O
reporters	O
after	O
her	O
visit	O
,	O
Mowlam	B-PER
apologized	O
to	O
people	O
who	O
took	O
offense	O
.	O

But	O
she	O
depicted	O
the	O
trip	O
as	O
part	O
of	O
her	O
commitment	O
to	O
do	O
whatever	O
it	O
takes	O
to	O
keep	O
the	O
peace	O
talks	O
on	O
track	O
.	O
"	O

If	O
we	O
manage	O
to	O
get	O
people	O
round	O
the	O
table	O
on	O
Monday	O
,	O
"	O
she	O
said	O
,	O
"	O
we	O
have	O
a	O
chance	O
to	O
move	O
this	O
process	O
forward	O
.	O
"	O

Mowlam	B-PER
denied	O
being	O
summoned	O
to	O
the	O
prison	O
or	O
submitting	O
to	O
guerrilla	O
threats	O
.	O
"	O

There	O
was	O
no	O
metaphorical	O
gun	O
at	O
my	O
head	O
,	O
"	O
she	O
said	O
.	O

She	O
also	O
denied	O
offering	O
the	O
prisoners	O
any	O
concessions	O
.	O

Rather	O
,	O
she	O
said	O
,	O
she	O
delivered	O
a	O
message	O
that	O
their	O
concerns	O
--	O
particularly	O
that	O
their	O
release	O
be	O
part	O
of	O
any	O
peace	O
accord	O
--	O
could	O
be	O
addressed	O
only	O
if	O
talks	O
continue	O
.	O

Currently	O
,	O
539	O
people	O
convicted	O
of	O
offenses	O
related	O
to	O
the	O
sectarian	O
conflict	O
live	O
in	O
the	O
huge	O
walled	O
facility	O
known	O
as	O
the	O
Maze	O
.	O

Their	O
influence	O
in	O
the	O
talks	O
is	O
among	O
the	O
starker	O
paradoxes	O
of	O
the	O
conflict	O
.	O

Though	O
the	O
British	B-GPE
government	O
keeps	O
them	O
locked	O
up	O
,	O
it	O
must	O
also	O
keep	O
in	O
mind	O
their	O
views	O
,	O
because	O
they	O
are	O
viewed	O
as	O
heroes	O
and	O
prisoners	O
of	O
war	O
by	O
many	O
people	O
on	O
the	O
outside	O
.	O

Their	O
approval	O
is	O
considered	O
key	O
to	O
any	O
settlement	O
.	O

About	O
half	O
the	O
prisoners	O
are	O
members	O
of	O
the	O
outlawed	O
Irish	B-ORG
Republican	I-ORG
Army	I-ORG
and	O
its	O
spinoffs	O
,	O
which	O
want	O
Northern	B-GPE
Ireland	I-GPE
to	O
become	O
part	O
of	O
Ireland	B-GPE
.	O

The	O
others	O
are	O
members	O
of	O
various	O
illegal	O
loyalist	O
armed	O
groups	O
that	O
want	O
Northern	B-GPE
Ireland	I-GPE
to	O
remain	O
a	O
British	B-GPE
province	O
.	O

The	O
prisoners	O
affiliated	O
with	O
the	O
Ulster	B-ORG
Defense	I-ORG
Association	I-ORG
and	O
Ulster	B-ORG
Freedom	I-ORG
Fighters	I-ORG
became	O
the	O
focus	O
of	O
the	O
crisis	O
in	O
recent	O
days	O
.	O

Angry	O
over	O
the	O
murder	O
of	O
a	O
hard-line	O
loyalist	O
leader	O
in	O
the	O
Maze	O
and	O
the	O
release	O
of	O
IRA	B-ORG
prisoners	O
in	O
the	O
Irish	B-GPE
republic	I-GPE
,	O
they	O
voted	O
to	O
withdraw	O
support	O
for	O
the	O
talks	O
.	O

A	O
statement	O
issued	O
by	O
the	O
two	O
groups	O
after	O
Mowlam	B-PER
's	O
visit	O
said	O
they	O
had	O
reversed	O
their	O
previous	O
vote	O
,	O
but	O
added	O
that	O
this	O
"	O
does	O
not	O
represent	O
a	O
change	O
in	O
our	O
assessment	O
of	O
the	O
talks	O
.	O
"	O

Many	O
members	O
of	O
the	O
Protestant	B-ORG
community	O
feel	O
frustrated	O
over	O
the	O
talks	O
,	O
saying	O
that	O
Catholics	B-PER
are	O
getting	O
all	O
the	O
concessions	O
.	O

On	O
Thursday	O
,	O
in	O
an	O
attempt	O
to	O
dispel	O
reports	O
that	O
the	O
prisoners	O
are	O
virtually	O
in	O
charge	O
at	O
the	O
Maze	O
,	O
prison	O
authorities	O
opened	O
the	O
doors	O
to	O
British	B-GPE
journalists	O
and	O
cameras	O
.	O

Inside	O
they	O
filmed	O
barbed	O
wire	O
,	O
tall	O
walls	O
and	O
other	O
security	O
measures	O
--	O
and	O
prisoner	O
living	O
areas	O
that	O
were	O
done	O
up	O
as	O
paramilitary	O
barracks	O
.	O

Unit	O
names	O
,	O
coats	O
of	O
arms	O
,	O
militant	O
slogans	O
and	O
pictures	O
of	O
masked	O
men	O
with	O
automatic	O
weapons	O
had	O
been	O
painted	O
on	O
walls	O
.	O
